[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "The property of being liquefied due to heat is known as ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) stress",
            "b) contraction",
            "c) normalizing",
            "d) fusibility"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The property of being liquefied due to heat is known as fusibility. Contraction is the reduction in length of material and stress is the load on the material."
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "Which of the following property of a material is preferred in the construction of an aircraft?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ductility",
            "b) Elasticity",
            "c) Hardness",
            "d) High density"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The point is called the proportional limit. Beyond the proportional limit, stress is not proportional to strain. Yield point denotes the point after which the material turns to plastic. Rupture strength and yield point occur after the proportional limit."
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "What is the temperature at which steel fuses?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1100°F",
            "b) 200K",
            "c) 2500°F",
            "d) 3500°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hardness is directly proportional to strength. As the hardness of a material increases, it’s strength increases. Hardness is the tendency of a material to resist penetration. Strength of a material is its capacity to withstand a load."
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "Why do metals contract and expand?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Due to cooling and heating",
            "b) Due to displacement",
            "c) Due to repairs",
            "d) Due to false recognition"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Ductility, elasticity and hardness are all preferred in the construction of an aircraft. High density is not preferred. Instead, low density is preferred."
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "A material elongated to 35m due to certain conditions. If it’s initial length is 7m, what is the strain of the material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 21m",
            "b) 5m",
            "c) 7m",
            "d) 35m"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Steel fuses at around 2500°F. Aluminium alloys fuse at around 1100°F. Fusibility is the liquefaction of a material due to heat."
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "The tendency of a material to fracture without changing it’s shape is known as ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) brittleness",
            "b) hardness",
            "c) elasticity",
            "d) carburizing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The cooling and heating of metals causes contraction and expansion respectively. That is the reason why railway tracks expand in summer."
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "If a material is loaded beyond its elastic limit _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) it returns back to it’s original shape",
            "b) it acquires softness",
            "c) it is permanently distorted",
            "d) it turns to liquid"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Strain = \\(\\frac{Change \\,in \\,length}{Original \\,length} \n= \\frac{35}{7}\\) = 5m."
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "The property of a material involving transmitting of heat or electricity is known as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) expansion",
            "b) stress",
            "c) contraction",
            "d) conduction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The tendency of a material to fracture without changing it’s shape is known as brittleness. Hardness of a material is its tendency to resist penetration. Elasticity of a material is the property of the material to return to its original shape once the force causing the distortion of shape is removed."
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "The load obtained in a tension test is 500N and the original cross sectional area is 250m2 what is the tensile strength of the material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 m",
            "b) 25 N/m2",
            "c) 2 N/m2",
            "d) 20 m"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The yield point is a point after which there is an increase in deformation without a load increase. Steel is one the few materials that has a definite yield point."
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "The modulus of elasticity of a material can be described as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) the product of stress and strain",
            "b) the ratio of stress to strain",
            "c) the product of yield point and strain",
            "d) the ratio of change in length to original length"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If a material is loaded beyond its elastic limit, it is permanently distorted. Elastic limit is the extent up to which a material can withstand stress without deforming permanently."
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "The ability of a material to resist permanent distortion or penetration is called as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) hardness",
            "b) yield point",
            "c) malleability",
            "d) elongation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The property of a material involving transmitting of heat or electricity is known as conduction. It is also a property to be considered in aircraft electrical bonding."
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "What is the total permissible elongation for a gage length of 5.08cm?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5080 cm",
            "b) 0.00508 cm",
            "c) 0.508 cm",
            "d) 0.000508 cm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Tensile strength = \\(\\frac{Maximum \\,load \\,obtained}{Original \\,cross-sectional \\,area}\\) \n= \\(\\frac{500}{250}\\) = 2 N/m2."
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "What is the effect of heat treatment on a metal?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improvement in availability",
            "b) Improved physical properties",
            "c) Decreased color",
            "d) Decreased availability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Heat treatment improves/changes the physical properties of a given metal. It is a set of processes involving several different methods like hardening, drawing, etc. Heat treatment does not affect the availability of the metal."
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "Carburizing is ideally carried out on steels that have less than __________ carbon content.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 90%",
            "b) 50%",
            "c) 10%",
            "d) 25%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quenching is the process of cooling a metal by submerging it in a liquid. It is a heat treatment process. The liquids used in this method are typically water or oil. It increases the strength of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "Annealing a metal ________ its internal strains.",
        "Options": [
            "a) doesn’t affect",
            "b) removes",
            "c) increases",
            "d) doubles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Carburizing is a process in which carbon is added to steel, by heating it in contact with a carbon-bearing material at a high temperature. Carburizing Is ideally carried out on steels that have less than 25% carbon content."
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "Casehardening refers to _________ the material, after which necessary heat treatment is done to it.",
        "Options": [
            "a) annealing",
            "b) critical range",
            "c) carburizing",
            "d) hardening"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Annealing a metal is heating it uniformly and then cooling it slowly. This alters the internal arrangement of atoms. Annealing is known to remove internal strains and decrease the hardness of the metal. "
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "In the process of hardening of steel, the metal has to be heated to a temperature ______ the critical range.",
        "Options": [
            "a) below",
            "b) half",
            "c) above",
            "d) around"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In casehardening, the material has to first undergo carburizing. Then, the material is subjected to heat treatment. This is done to harden the surface of the material. Critical range is a range of temperatures at which the structure of a metal changes."
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "In the process of the hardening of aluminum alloys, what is the temperature above which it should be heated?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1200°F",
            "b) 600°F",
            "c) 2400°F",
            "d) 900°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the process of hardening of steel, the metal has to be heated to a temperature above the critical range. Hardening increases the strength of the material. In order to alter the internal atomic structure of the steel to change its properties, heating it above the critical range is required."
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "Which heat treatment method is also called as “drawing”?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tempering",
            "b) Casehardening",
            "c) Annealing",
            "d) Normalizing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Normalizing is a heat treatment method of steel. It closely resembles annealing. But, compared to annealing it is faster and makes the material stronger. Also, annealing is done for several materials."
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "The critical range of steel is between ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1300°F and 1600°F",
            "b) 2400°F and 2600°F",
            "c) 900°F and 2800°F",
            "d) 900°F and 2400°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: When a material is heated beyond its critical range, and subsequently undergoes the process of quenching it is called Hardening. Aluminum alloys are heated above temperatures of 900°F to be hardened."
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "Materials with ______________ are typically used in aircraft construction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) no strain",
            "b) lower strength/weight ratio",
            "c) average strength/weight ratio",
            "d) higher strength/weight ratio"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The strength/weight ratio is an indication of the material’s ability to sustain the load. Materials with high weight are not preferred. Material with high strength and low weight have good strength/weight ratio, hence they are used."
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a property of aluminium that makes it ideal to use as an aircraft material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Resistance to corrosion",
            "b) Light in weight",
            "c) High fuel consumption",
            "d) High strength alloy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: High fuel consumption is not an advantage. Moreover, aluminium has a low fuel consumption. It is light in weight compared to other metals like steel. It is also a high strength alloy. It is resistant to corrosion."
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "Which of the following methods would be helpful if a material that is not resistant to corrosion is used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Painting a protective layer",
            "b) Heating to 10°F",
            "c) Increase the quantity of material",
            "d) Disjoining"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Materials with a good joining property are an advantage. The joining property of a material is the ability to manufacture a structural joint by mechanical methods or welding, soldering, etc. It is useful in fabrication."
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "Why is low thermal conductivity important for aircraft systems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To increase the strength of the material",
            "b) To protect from excessive heating",
            "c) To keep aircraft warm for passengers",
            "d) For oxygen"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Materials that are not resistant to corrosion can be painted with a protective layer of another metal. A few examples of metals are chromium, nickel or zinc. Increasing the quantity of material or heating will not help."
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "What is fatigue strength?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Strength/weight ratio",
            "b) Elasticity",
            "c) Resistance to cyclical stress",
            "d) Strain energy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Thermal conductivity of a material is the rate at which it conducts heat. Low thermal conductivity is important because it prevents the systems from excessive heating hence preventing failure. It does not affect the oxygen levels or increase the strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "What does a good working property of material mean?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To have high strength",
            "b) To be able to bend or machine the material in the desired shape",
            "c) To have a corrosive nature",
            "d) To ability to join the material in the desired shape"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The highest point up to which the material can resist cycles of stress. Aircraft are affected by several stresses and loads. It is important to consider their resistance to these loads and stresses to avoid failure."
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a mechanical property of materials?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Color",
            "b) Appearance",
            "c) Reliability",
            "d) Elasticity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Landing gear wheels are made of thick rubber. This is to absorb the shock waves and vibration caused when landing an aircraft. It also prevents the loss of fluids. Rubber is a good nonmetallic component of aircraft."
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "An aircraft material should be resistant to ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) join",
            "b) work",
            "c) shock loads",
            "d) strength"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The working property of a material is the ability to change its shape in the required form. The ability to join the material is called joining property. They are important in the fabrication of aircraft parts."
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "Why is the reliability of a material an important property?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To maintain material cost",
            "b) To maintain the quality of material",
            "c) To obtain old stock material",
            "d) To consider supplementary material"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Reliability of a material is important to maintain the quality of the material. The material has to be manufactured by a standard manufacturer that produces good quality material to ensure that the material is not easily damaged."
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an economic consideration of a material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Structure",
            "b) Appearance",
            "c) Availability",
            "d) Strain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The availability of material is an economic consideration. The material being used for the construction of an aircraft must be available for all requirements. Structure and appearance are physical properties of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "What is a supplementary operation requirement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The availability of extra material if the original material is damaged",
            "b) A material that requires supplementary operations to be used in manufacturing",
            "c) The operations that are not necessary to perform",
            "d) Operations that have to be avoided"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Porosity is the quantity of void space present in the structure of a material. It is the ratio of pore volume to the total structure volume. It is one of the physical properties of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a technological factor of materials?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Castability",
            "b) Melting point",
            "c) Availability",
            "d) Stress"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A material that requires supplementary operations before being used in manufacturing is called supplementary operational requirement. The operations vary depending on the material. A few examples are plating, heat treatment etc. The materials cannot be used in their natural state. This is a disadvantage as it is more costly and time-consuming."
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "The dimension of material is considered to be a _____________ property.",
        "Options": [
            "a) physical",
            "b) technological",
            "c) mechanical",
            "d) economic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Castability is a technological factor of materials. The ease with which the material can be cast is called castability. The higher the castability, easier the process. Melting point and availability are physical properties of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "What is the foamability of a material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The act of increasing the amount of material",
            "b) The ability to make a soldered joint",
            "c) Anti-foaming agents in a material",
            "d) The amount of capability to produce foam"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The dimension of a material is a physical property. Dimension is the physical measurement of an object. Length, breadth and height describe the dimensions of an object. It is not an economic, technological or mechanical property."
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "Is the standardization of materials advantageous?",
        "Options": [
            "a) No, it is harmful to the aircraft",
            "b) Only for the wheels of the aircraft",
            "c) Yes, it is advantageous",
            "d) It has never been done before"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Cost should not be the only and primary consideration in the selection of materials. The materials that have good properties like high strength /weight ratio must be selected, and cost can be a factor of selection among them later in the process. The quality of material must not be compromised due to cost."
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "Which of the following factors is least considered in the selection of materials for aircraft construction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Color",
            "b) Melting point",
            "c) Weldability",
            "d) Elasticity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The capability to produce foam is called the foamability of a material. The ability of a material to be made into soldered joints easily is called solderability of a material. Both foamability and solderability are technological factors of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "What is the machinability of a material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lack of material",
            "b) Ease of cutting a material",
            "c) Shining the material",
            "d) Shrinking the material"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Standardization of materials is an advantage. It refers to using the available material in manufacturing different components, instead of stocking several materials that result in residual materials being left."
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "Which cost of the Shop equipment required should be considered?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Comparative cost",
            "b) Initial cost",
            "c) Maintenance cost",
            "d) Maintenance cost plus the initial cost"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Color is the least considered factor in the selection of materials. The technological, physical and economic factors like melting point, weldability and availability are much more important as they affect safety and performance more. Also, materials can be colored according to requirements."
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": "What is the fuselage of an aircraft made of?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pure iron",
            "b) Acrylic",
            "c) Aluminium alloy",
            "d) Magnesium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The fuselage of an aircraft is typically made of aluminium alloys. The fuselage is the mainframe of an aircraft. Aluminium alloy is chosen because it has favorable properties, like high ductility, high strength/weight ratio etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "Which of the following materials is used in making aircraft windows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Thick glass",
            "b) Plexiglass",
            "c) Graphite",
            "d) Plane glass"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Plexiglass is the material used in making aircraft windows. It is preferred instead of plane glass. It has attractive properties, like its strength and transparency. Aircraft windows are made of several layers."
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "What is the thickness of the sheets used in manufacturing oil tanks?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.5 to 26 mm",
            "b) 0.889 to 1.2446 mm",
            "c) 5.9 to 10.21 mm",
            "d) 0.5 to 0.7 mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Magnesium and its alloys are suitable to use while making helicopters. This is because it is lighter in weight compared to aluminium. It is a good structural metal to use. But it is not resistant to corrosion."
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be used as wing covering in an aircraft?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Manganese alloy",
            "b) Carbon",
            "c) Titanium",
            "d) Aluminium alloy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Oil tanks are usually made with aluminium or its alloys, although magnesium can also be used. The thickness of the sheets used is somewhere between 0.889 to 12.446 mm. The thickness depends upon various parameters like shape, size, etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "Controls can be made using _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) wood",
            "b) copper",
            "c) steel",
            "d) flaps"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Aluminum alloy can be used as a covering for wings in an aircraft. There are other materials that can be used, like fabric and plywood. Carbon, titanium and manganese alloy are not used for this purpose."
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be used to make seats in an aircraft?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Magnesium alloy sheets",
            "b) Graphite",
            "c) Rubber",
            "d) Pure magnesium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Controls can be made using either steel or aluminium alloys. Controls refer to the control parts of an aircraft like control sticks, torsion tubes, bell-cranks etc. Wood and copper are not used."
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "Metals like chrome-molybdenum steel are heated to a temperature of ____________ to make bushings.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 500 or 750 psi",
            "b) 1000 psi",
            "c) 650,000 or 7000,000 psi",
            "d) 125,000 or 150,000 psi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aircraft seats are made using magnesium alloy sheets. Aluminium alloy sheets can also be used. Pure magnesium is not used, as alloyed metals typically have preferable properties compared to elements in their pure state."
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "Bolts in an aircraft are made of _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) nickel steel",
            "b) graphite",
            "c) aluminium",
            "d) iron"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Bushings are manufactured by heating metals like chrome-molybdenum steel to a temperature of 125,000 or 150,000 psi. Bushings can be replaced by new parts once they are worn out."
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not used to manufacture a wing-tip bow?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Chrome-molybdenum",
            "b) Aluminium alloy",
            "c) Douglas fir",
            "d) Mild steel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Wood is used in manufacturing several parts of an aircraft. It is used in propeller blades, wing ribs etc. Plywood is used in making parts like wing leading edge, flooring, etc. Wing beams can be made of several types of woods like Douglas fir, poplar etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "What are the wheels of a landing great made of?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Typical rubber",
            "b) Sensitive rubber",
            "c) Titanium alloy",
            "d) Thick rubber"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Nickel steels are used in making bolts of an aircraft. Bolts are used in structural connections. Bolts made of nickel steel have higher Strength compared to chrome-molybdenum bolts, which are used if there is a requirement of welding as nickel steel is not easy to weld."
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "Which of the following specification is used in manufacturing fuselage, oil tank and wings of an aircraft?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1111-Z",
            "b) 2024-T4",
            "c) 2011-X2",
            "d) 1214-A"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Wing-tip bows can be manufactured using chrome-molybdenum, aluminium alloy and mild steel. However, Douglas fir is not used. Douglas fir is a type of tree whose wood can be used in manufacturing wing beams."
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "Which of the following components is/are used in making aircraft wings?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Titanium alloys",
            "b) Graphite",
            "c) Aluminium alloys",
            "d) Titanium alloys and aluminium alloys"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The wheels of landing gear are made of thick rubber. This is to absorb any shocks. The other part of the landing gear contains titanium alloys. The wheels are pumped with gases like nitrogen to avoid explosions."
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "Non-metallic materials are primarily used in manufacturing _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) fuselage",
            "b) engine",
            "c) wing tips and stabilizer tips",
            "d) seats"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 2024-T4 is used in manufacturing several components of an aircraft like the fuselage, oil tank and wings. It is used in wing covering, wing ribs, wing leading edge, wing beams, etc. 2024-T4 is a type of aluminium alloy. It is a part of the 2000 series of aluminium alloy."
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "What is the variation to which the tension testing machine must be sensitive?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1/250 of the registered load",
            "b) 1/100 of registered load",
            "c) 1/500 of registered load",
            "d) 1/200 of the registered load"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To obtain an accurate result, it is important for the test machine to be in appropriate condition. One of the important conditions is for a load being applied, the test machine must be sensitive to a variation of 1/250."
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "Which of the following can be obtained through a tension test?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Colour",
            "b) Heat treatment",
            "c) Ultimate tensile strength",
            "d) Conductivity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Tension testing can provide a lot of basic information about the property of the material being tested. Ultimate tensile strength is obtained through tension testing. It is the withstanding ability of a material to load. Tensile refers to bring pulled away."
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "During tension testing, the material must be held in _____________ alignment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) normal",
            "b) axial",
            "c) parallel",
            "d) diabolical"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The material or the specimen should be positioned in true axial alignment. This is considered vital, especially since materials used in aircraft construction are thin. This will avoid damaging them."
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "The elastic limit of a material is _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) the least amount of stress that can be held without permanent deformation",
            "b) highest stress a material can experience without permanent deformation",
            "c) average stress experienced by material in its lifeline.",
            "d) strain on material"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Extensometer is an instrument used to measure the change in the length of a material. It should not be placed anywhere to the specimen. It should be fixed at the gage marks of the specimen being tested in the testing machine."
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "In the tension testing experiment, while determining elastic limit, the increment, while the load is being increased, should not exceed ___________ % of the elastic limit in the ending.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 50",
            "b) 7",
            "c) 2",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The elastic limit is the highest stress that a material can withstand, without permanent deformation present when the stress is released completely. It is not the lowest amount of stress present."
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "The tension testing machine (crosshead) should not cross a speed of ___________ inch per inch of the gage length per minute until the yield point.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1/11",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 1/16",
            "d) 2/5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the tension testing experiment, we can determine the elastic limit. Here the load is applied gradually in different points to determine the elastic limit. In the final part of the experiment, the load being increased should not exceed 3% of the elastic limit."
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "It is possible to determine the proof stress in a way in which ___________ is determined.",
        "Options": [
            "a) elastic limit",
            "b) yield point",
            "c) stress",
            "d) strain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The crosshead of the tension testing machine has a certain advisable limit in speed it has to be operated up to. It is different until the yield point and after yield point till rupture. Until yield point it is 1/16 inch, yield point to rupture it is 1/2 inch. (Inch per inch)"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "For a 4-inch gage length, crosshead speed of a machine should not exceed ___________ inch up to yield point.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1/16",
            "b) 1/4",
            "c) 1/8",
            "d) 1/6"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The proof stress of a material can be found or determined the same way the elastic limit can be determined. But, there are other methods through which the elastic limit can be found as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "A materials proof stress is the highest stress possible for it to tolerate without causing a permanent set of more than ___________ inch per inch the length of gage, after the total release of stress.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5.1",
            "b) 0.002",
            "c) 0.0001",
            "d) 0.1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The speed which a crosshead should not exceed until yield point is 1/16 for one inch per inch gage length per minute.\nFor 4 inches, it is – \\(\\frac{1×4}{16}\\) = 1/4 inch."
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "Why must an accurate extensometer be used in reading a permanent set?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is cheap",
            "b) To obtain accuracy",
            "c) It is radioactive",
            "d) It is unnecessary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘A’ is called the diameter of the centre of the specimen. Gage length is the horizontal distance marked on the specimen to signify the part that is under consideration. Stress meter is not present anywhere on the specimen."
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "The proof stress of a material of 3 inches gage length is the highest stress it can withstand without a permanent set of above ___________ inch.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.0003",
            "b) 0.21",
            "c) 0.05",
            "d) 0.004"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  The highest possible stress a material can, without causing a permanent set of more than 0.00001 inch per inch of the gage length is called proof stress. This is after the total release of the stress."
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "A materials proof stress is also referred to as ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) elastic limit",
            "b) yield limit",
            "c) proportional limit",
            "d) set method"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: An extensometer must be used in reading the permanent set. An accurate extensometer is required to obtain the change in the property after the experiment is done, without any mistakes or problems with accuracy."
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "Tension testing must be accurate within a percentage of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) +2%",
            "b) +1%",
            "c) +3/2 %",
            "d) 21%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Tension testing can give us crucial information regarding the properties of a material. Apart from the ultimate tensile strength, the yield strength and reduction in area can be determined through tension testing."
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "The yield strength of a material is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) the proof stress of a material",
            "b) the strain where the strength of material fails",
            "c) the elongation",
            "d) the particular stress where a material shows specified elongation under a load"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The process of tension testing must adhere to certain conditions to assure its validity. One of the conditions is the range of accuracy of the testing machine. The percentage within which the accuracy should be present is 3/2%."
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "What does length ‘AC’ in the diagram represent?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yield gage",
            "b) Yield strength",
            "c) Set",
            "d) Yield point"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The yield strength of a material is the particular stress where a material shows specified elongation under a load. The elongation of a material is the change in length before being affected by stress to after."
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "The extension under load method is easier to use in finding yield strength because ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) no necessity to plot a curve",
            "b) it is not easier",
            "c) it is the only method available",
            "d) randomness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Usually, the preferred method of determining yield strength can be used. It is not fixed. The two methods typically used to find the yield strength are set method and extension under load method."
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "The second part of specified extensions in the extensions under load method typically involves adding an elongation of ____ inch per inch of gage length.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.2",
            "b) 2.02",
            "c) 0.02",
            "d) 0.002"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The length AC is called the ‘set’ or gage length percentage. The graph represents yield strength determination through the set method. The yield strength is represented at the point ‘B’ in the graph."
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "If the expected yield strength of a material is 50,000 pounds per square inch and modulus of elasticity is 10,000, what is the normal elongation of the material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 50,000,000 inch per inch gage length",
            "b) 5 inch per inch gage length",
            "c) 50 inch per inch gage length",
            "d) 5 inch per inch gage length"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The extension under load method is used much more than the set method. This is due to the fact that the former method does not require the plotting of a curve to find the yield strength of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "The modulus of elasticity of steel is ____________ pounds per square inch.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6,500,000",
            "b) 10,000,000",
            "c) 30,000,000",
            "d) 1000,00"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The extensions under load method consists of two sections. First is elongation depending on the modulus of elasticity of object and expected yield strength and the second involves adding an extra elongation of 0.002 inch per inch gage length."
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "What is the yield point of a material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Change in the strain of a material",
            "b) The ratio of proof stress to the area",
            "c) The elasticity of a material",
            "d) Point where there is a substantial increase in elongation without a rise in load"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The formula of normal elongation is given by = \\(\\frac{Expected \\, yield\\, strength}{Modulus \\,of\\, elasticity}\\) \n= \\(\\frac{50,000}{10,000}\\) \n= 5 inches per inch gage length."
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "To obtain consistent results in finding properties of materials, the specimen must be/have __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) no scratches",
            "b) straightened",
            "c) washed with methyl",
            "d) bent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The modulus of elasticity of a material is used in determining the normal elongation of a material. The modulus of elasticity of steel is 30,000,000 pounds per square inch. For aluminium alloys, it is 10,000,000 Psi and for magnesium it is 6,500,000 psi."
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "The yield point can be determined in _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) wood",
            "b) carbon",
            "c) pure molybdenum",
            "d) mild carbon steel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: A materials yield point is the point where there is a significant increase in the elongation without an increment in the load. The yield point of a material can be determined in two ways – the divider method, and drop of beam method."
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "In which method is there usage of a pair of dividers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Set method",
            "b) Divider method",
            "c) Drop of beam method",
            "d) Dividend method"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For the experiment to work with the production of accurate results, the material must not contain scratches. It should not be straightened or bent as it will negatively affect the values of the experiment."
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "The yield point of a material does not exist for those materials that have a _____________ region in that space of the stress-strain curve.",
        "Options": [
            "a) smooth",
            "b) shift",
            "c) turbulent",
            "d) high"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The yield point is not present in all available materials. It is present in certain materials like Mild carbon steel and wrought iron. It does not exist in wood, pure carbon or pure molybdenum. There are two methods to determine the yield point of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "In which method of determination of yield point is the load applied uniformly on the beam?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Divider method",
            "b) High beam method",
            "c) Drop of beam method",
            "d) Extension under load method"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are two methods to determine the yield point of a material. One is divider method, and the other is drop of beam method. In that, drop of beam method uses a pair of dividers. Set method is a method of determination of yield strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a hardness testing method?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rockwell hardness",
            "b) Brinell hardness",
            "c) Set method hardness",
            "d) Shore scleroscope hardness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Hardness testing methods are processes to check the strength of the material. Rockwell hardness, Brinell hardness, Shore scleroscope hardness and Diamond pyramid hardness are typically used hardness tests. The set method is one of the methods used to determine the yield strength of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "It is vital that surfaces that have to be tested to determine the hardness of the material must be free of _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) ridges",
            "b) evenness",
            "c) smoothness",
            "d) thickness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In order to perform tests on the material, it must meet certain standards. It should have the required thickness to avoid bulging and must be free of ridges and scratches. It should be even and smooth."
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "For ____________ materials, there is no correspondence between tensile strength and hardness.",
        "Options": [
            "a) soft",
            "b) hard materials",
            "c) steel",
            "d) carbon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There is a relation between the hardness and tensile strength. The approximate value of the tensile strength of several materials can be found when the hardness of those materials is known."
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "The Brinell testing method uses a steel ball of __________ diameter for testing purposes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 26mm",
            "b) 1mm",
            "c) 10m",
            "d) 10mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There is a relation between hardness and tensile strength for materials like carbon and low alloy steels. The tensile strength can be predicted using hardness values. But for comparatively soft materials like aluminium alloys, this is not applicable."
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": "In the Brinell testing method, the load should be pressed for a minimum of ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1000 seconds",
            "b) 60 seconds",
            "c) 10 seconds",
            "d) 3 seconds"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There is a necessity to find the hardness of a material as it can give an indication of the strength and several other properties of a material. At the same time, it is important to avoid damaging the material as that would be a loss. Especially for a manufactured material."
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "If the load being applied is 2000kg, and the area of impression is 250 Square millimetres, what is the Brinell number of the test material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 80 kg per square millimeter",
            "b) 25 kg per square millimeter",
            "c) 20 kg per square millimeter",
            "d) 8 kg per square millimeter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Brinell test method involves pressing a hard ball made of steel, with a particular pressure onto the surface of the test specimen. The diameter of the steel ball being used is 10 mm."
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a way to prepare the test material for the Brinell hardness test?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Grinding",
            "b) Layering",
            "c) Filing",
            "d) Polishing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the Brinell testing method, the test specimen is indented with a ball made of steel, with a diameter or 10 mm for a certain amount of time. The minimum time period is 10 seconds before the load is released."
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "To perform Brinell test on a soft material like bronze _____________ kg of load is applied on the specimen.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3000",
            "b) 500",
            "c) 6600",
            "d) 1200"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Brinell hardness number = \\(\\frac{Load \\,Applied}{Area \\,of \\,impression \\,(spherical)}\\) \n= \\(\\frac{2000}{250}\\) \n= 8 kg per square millimeter."
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "Rockwell hardness test uses either a ____________ ball or ___________ cone for measuring hardness.",
        "Options": [
            "a) steel, diamond",
            "b) diamond, steel",
            "c) carbon, iron",
            "d) iron, carbon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The requirements of the specimen for Brinell testing method is similar to the remaining test methods. There are several ways to prepare the material for the test. Grinding, filing and polishing using emery paper are done. Layering is not one of the methods."
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "The Rockwell hardness testing method typically uses certain amounts of load. Which of the following is not one of the loads used?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 150kg",
            "b) 60kg",
            "c) 5kg",
            "d) 100kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Different amount of load are applied on test specimen depending upon the type of material being tested. For steel testing, the pressure applied is 3000kg. For comparatively softer materials like aluminium alloys, the pressure applied is 500kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "To find a true hardness reading for hard steel, the minimum thickness required for material is ____",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.0027mm",
            "b) 6.858mm",
            "c) 0.27mm",
            "d) 234mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Rockwell hardness value is found by calculating the penetration of either a steel ball or diamond cone under a particular load. The Rockwell hardness number appears on the dial of the machine."
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "In the beginning of the Rockwell hardness experiment, the reading dial is set to _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100",
            "b) 50",
            "c) 0.1",
            "d) 0"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The loads being applied in the Rockwell hardness method usually on the penetrator(steel ball or diamond cone) being used and the test specimen. The loads applied are typically 100kg, 150kg and 60kg."
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "Which of the following hardness testing method is preferred for aircraft manufacturing purposes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Brinell hardness",
            "b) Rockwell hardness",
            "c) Divider method",
            "d) Shore scleroscope hardness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To obtain the Rockwell hardness value, the loads used or penetrators depends on the weather the material is soft or hard. The minimum thickness required for hard steel is 6.858mm. This will give an accurate hardness value."
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a process or property that influences the hardness of a material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Buffing",
            "b) Storing",
            "c) Porous areas",
            "d) Decarburizing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Due to the properties of the material, the hardness and subsequently tensile strength are affected. Processes like buffing influence the surface of the material. Porous areas and decarburizing also affect the material."
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "What should be done to avoid deflection caused by depression?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plating",
            "b) Unique direction",
            "c) Smooth surface",
            "d) Required edge distance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Deflection caused due to depression is one of the possibilities that have to be considered and avoided to obtain the correct result. It can be avoided by ensuring that the experiment is being conducted at the required edge distance."
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "The Vickers hardness test consists of a _________ penetrator.",
        "Options": [
            "a) diamond",
            "b) steel ball",
            "c) carbon",
            "d) iron"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The statement is incorrect. Hardness testing machines don not give the exact same results. Even if they are similar in type, obtaining exact same results every time is not possible."
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "The penetrator in the Vickers hardness test is a pyramid that is squarely based and has an included angle of _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) 206°",
            "b) 15°",
            "c) 136°",
            "d) 23°"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A diamond penetrator is used in a Vickers/diamond pyramid hardness test. The penetrator consists of a pyramid that has a square base. A Steel ball is used in Brinell and Rockwell hardness tests."
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "The loading used for a homogenous specimen in the bucket’s hardness test is _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) 30kg",
            "b) 500kg",
            "c) 5kg",
            "d) 13kg"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The included angle of the square based, pyramid diamond penetrator in the Vickers/diamond hardness test is 136°. 15° and 23° would be too low of an angle to be considered."
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "The shore scleroscope hardness test is carried out by ________ a tiny diamond-pointed hammer from a particular altitude and comparing the altitude of rebound to a standard test material.",
        "Options": [
            "a) inserting",
            "b) cutting",
            "c) smoothly pressing",
            "d) dropping"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the Vickers/diamond hardness test, the amount of load applied typically on homogenous material is 30kg. 5kg is the weight applied to materials that are soft or those that have a hard surface."
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "Which if the following is suggested in the shore scleroscope test to obtain the exact value?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Instrument should be in sunlight",
            "b) Instrument should be spray painted",
            "c) Instrument should be fixed rigidly",
            "d) Instrument should be in sleeping position"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: This hardness test is carried out by comparing the rebound altitude of the test material after dropping a tiny diamond pointed hammer on the test specimen, to that of a standard test material."
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "In case of shore scleroscope hardness, the number considered is the average of __________ determinations.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 26",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 333"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The instrument should be fixed rigidly in a particular position to avoid movement during the experiment. If any movement happens, it might affect the accuracy of the obtained hardness number."
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "Brinell hardness numbers of materials are identical to ________ hardness numbers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Set method",
            "b) Extension under load",
            "c) Shore scleroscope",
            "d) Vickers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The shore scleroscope number is obtained by conducting the experiment 5 times and taking an average of the obtained 5 values. The final obtained average value is considered shore scleroscope number."
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "Bending tests are conducted to ensure that the material has enough _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) force",
            "b) hardness",
            "c) impact",
            "d) ductility"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Bending tests are conducted to obtain the ductility of material and make sure that it does not have more brittleness than ductility. The hardness test is conducted to measure the hardness of the material."
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "Specimens in the bending test are usually ________ inches long.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 23",
            "b) 16",
            "c) 6",
            "d) 0.564"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The usual length of the bending test specimen, which is sheets or strips is 6 inches long. The specimen should not contain rough spots or edges, as that can effect the material and hence the experiment."
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "If the specimen being tested is heavy in weight, it should have a __________ cross-section.",
        "Options": [
            "a) circular",
            "b) spherical",
            "c) rectangular",
            "d) triangular"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For a specimen being tested that is heavy in weight, the rectangular cross section should be present. The cross section can be obtained by applying a smooth file at the corner of the test specimen."
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "The usual angle through which bending should be obtained in a bending test is ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 180°",
            "b) 120°",
            "c) 75°",
            "d) 90°"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The usual angle with which the test specimen should be bent in the bending test is 180°. This is over a pin that has the same diameter as that of the test specimen being used in the experiment. Cracking should be avoided."
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "The minimum length of wire that can be used in a reverse bend test is ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5 inches",
            "b) 23 inches",
            "c) 10 inches",
            "d) 4.5 inches"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is not very effortless or easy to obtain the exact desired radius of bending in the bending test being performed. But this test can often be used in shops etc. to check the properties of the material if there is a doubt about them."
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "_________ usually undergoes a reverse bend test.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Round steel wire",
            "b) Glue",
            "c) Plated iron",
            "d) Wood"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the reverse band test, the minimum length of wire used in the experiment is 10 inches. The specifications to perform the experiment on the specimen truly depend on the nature of the material."
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "The radius to which the jaws of the vice rounded to for wires of diameter less than 3/16 inches is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2/15",
            "b) 12/7",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 3/16"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Round steel wire is usually the most widely used specimen while performing the reverse bend test in laboratories. Wood and glue cannot be used or have the bending test performed on them."
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "The maximum rate up to which bending is done per minute is ________ in reverse bend test.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 35",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 50",
            "d) 26"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If the diameter of the wire in which the test is being carried out is less than 3/16 inches of diameter, the jaws of the vice are rounded to 3/16 inches. For wires of greater weight, the vice is set to 3 times the diameter of the wire."
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "What is the rate of bending carried out for heavy wires?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 65 bending’s",
            "b) 7 bending’s",
            "c) 80 bending’s",
            "d) 50 bending’s"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The maximum speed up to which the bending experiment can be conducted in the reverse band test is 50 bends per minute. This should be done while considering how it could be prone to heating."
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "A bend of what angle is considered as a single bend?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 45°",
            "b) 90°",
            "c) 180°",
            "d) 270°"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For heavy wire, the rate of bending in the reverse bend test is 7 bends per minute. For small wire, the rate of bending in the experiment is fifty bends per minute. This is the specification given."
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "Flattening test is applied to __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) twisting",
            "b) round steel wire",
            "c) tubing",
            "d) breaking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Flattening test is typically applicable for tubing. Round steel wire generally undergoes reverse bend test. Both of these are methods used to find the nature of the material, more specifically the ductility."
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "In the flattening test, the length of the tubing is taken _________ times of the diameter.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 0.5",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The flattening test is generally applied for tubing. It gives an idea about the ductility of the material. In this test, the length of the tube is taken as two times the diameter. It is flattened in a sideways direction and scrutinized to detect any defects."
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "The flattening test while being used for bronze tubing must consider the thickness of the tube to be not more than ____ times wall thickness.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 4",
            "d) 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In a flattening test, the maximum limit up to which the thickness of the tube can be considered is three times the thickness of the wall. This is in the case of bronze tubing in flattening test."
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "The specimen used in the typical bend test (sheet) must have a width of _______ inches.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12",
            "b) 4",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 0.56"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There is typically no such particular requirement that the specimen of the bending test must be taken only parallel to the grain. It is often required for the specimen to be taken in both parallel and across the grain."
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "It is usually preferred for shop bending to take all the present bends ________ grain.",
        "Options": [
            "a) across",
            "b) above",
            "c) below",
            "d) parallel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The specimen being used in the bending test, if it’s a sheet or strip stock typically has a width of one inch. The general length of the specimen considered is six inches. The edges of the specimen should not contain rough spots."
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "The edges of a specimen of forging stock are rounded to a ________ radius in a bending test.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20th",
            "b) 16th",
            "c) 1",
            "d) 1/16th"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the case of shop bending, it is usually preferred that all the bends be made across the grain. Once the test specimen passes the bending test, it is assured that the material is of good quality and there is a diminished possibility of cracking."
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "The bending in the bending tests is achieved be either__________ or __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) lightly rolling and tossing",
            "b) application of pressure and blow from a hammer",
            "c) ethanol and methane",
            "d) diamond indenting and washing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The specimens of forging stock also undergo the bending test. They are machined to a minimum of six inches in length. Their edges are rounded to a one by sixteenth radius. It differs for heavy material."
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "If the bend of a bend test has to be gauged to its complete extent _________ of bend must be computed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) inner circumference",
            "b) the inner minus outer circumference",
            "c) outer circumference",
            "d) inner radius"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The bending in the bending test is usually achieved by either applying a constant source of pressure or by delivering blows from a hammer. The usage of the hammer creates a much higher impact on the specimen than the other method."
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "What is an impact test?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fixing a specimen in the machine to be broken by weight or heavy pendulum",
            "b) Indenting with the help of a diamond hammer",
            "c) Rolling with steel",
            "d) Dipping in a mixture of ethanol and carbon and checking indentation of a material"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An impact test is a procedure that involves notching a specimen on one side and fastening it to a machine to be broken, either by a swinging pendulum that is heavy or by a falling weight on it."
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "The impact tests can be used to _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) find out the absolute value of a material",
            "b) to determine the tensile strength of a material",
            "c) compare two specimens of similar composition and tensile strength",
            "d) to find the quantity of material"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The impact test can be used to compare two specimens that have a similar composition and tensile strength. It has no absolute value. The test used to determine the tensile strength of a material is the tension test."
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "What is the principal use of the impact tests?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To determine ductility",
            "b) To determine if the material has been subjected to heat treatment",
            "c) To prevent material from corroding",
            "d) To obtain absolute values"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The principal or main reason that the impact test is conducted upon a material is to ascertain if the material has undergone the required accurate heat treatment. The experiment gives no absolute value."
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "On _________ materials, impact test cannot be conducted.",
        "Options": [
            "a) steel",
            "b) solid",
            "c) room temperature",
            "d) extremely ductile"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The statement is not true as the impact test does not determine the shock resistance of the particular material. The impact test can indicate if the material is extremely brittle. It also tells us if a material has undergone the right heat treatment or not."
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "In an Izod test after the pendulum is released from a certain height, it hits the material at the __________ point of it’s path.",
        "Options": [
            "a) lowest",
            "b) opposite",
            "c) highest",
            "d) sideways"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The impact test cannot be conducted in the required way on materials that are extremely ductile. This is due to the fact that these types of materials bend while breaking. The experiment can be conducted in room temperature."
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "If in an old test, energy absorbed (obtained on the scale) is 34 J and cross-section area of the notch is 10×8 mm square. What is the impact strength of the material?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 34 J per mm square",
            "b) 4.25 J per mm square",
            "c) 0.425 J per mm square",
            "d) 80 J per mm square"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In an Izod test, the material is first notched. Then it is clamped in heavy jaws, where the notch level is with the top and facing the pendulum. After the pendulum is released from a certain height, it hits the material at the lowest point of its path."
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "The higher the impact value of the material __________ its toughness value.",
        "Options": [
            "a) lower",
            "b) double",
            "c) half",
            "d) higher"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘A’ is called the notch angle of a specimen. In an Izod test, the notch angle is 45°. The angle of the notch is an important factor in determining the reaction a material shows when the test is done on it."
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "Which of the following are standard impact tests?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Izod test and flattening test",
            "b) Izod test and Charpy test",
            "c) Flattening test and reverse bend",
            "d) Charpy test and reverse bend test"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Charpy impact test and the Izod impact test are Standard impact tests. They have some differences, but they both give the impact values of the specimen. Reverse bend tests and flattening test are bending tests."
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "Which of the following impact test method is preferred these days?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Impact test",
            "b) Reverse bend test",
            "c) Flattening test",
            "d) Charpy test"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The method commonly preferred these days is the Charpy impact test. The Izod impact test has also been extensively used in the past. It is rarely used for testing materials/specimen these days."
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "In the Charpy test, the tensile specimen being tested is ___________ on both sides.",
        "Options": [
            "a) threaded",
            "b) axed",
            "c) flattened",
            "d) heated"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The tensile specimen in the Charpy impact test is threaded on both sides. One of the ends is threaded to the pendulum that is swinging. It is not axed, heated or subjected to any such treatment before being tested."
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "The Charpy test, which is a type of impact test measures the __________ absorbed by a specimen.",
        "Options": [
            "a) heat",
            "b) energy",
            "c) length",
            "d) breadth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Charpy test, like an Izod test, gives the energy absorbed by the specimen/material being tested. This is used to obtain the comparative properties of the desired materials. It also tells if the material is extremely brittle."
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "In the Charpy test, the notch faces _________ from the pendulum.",
        "Options": [
            "a) towards",
            "b) 20m",
            "c) away",
            "d) around"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the Charpy test, the notch faces away from the pendulum. This differs from the other impact test, the Izod impact test. This is one of the several differences between the two impact test methods."
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "The final impact value is obtained by dividing the _________ by the cross-sectional area in the Charpy test.",
        "Options": [
            "a) heat of the specimen",
            "b) cross-sectional damage",
            "c) energy of fracture",
            "d) cross-sectional area"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The above diagram represents a U-notch type specimen of a Charpy impact test. In this test method, there are primarily two kinds of test specimens. The U-notch test specimen and the V-notch test specimen."
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "Which of the following affects a Charpy test?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Specimen gauges factor",
            "b) Test machine frequency",
            "c) Colour",
            "d) Yield strength"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This statement is incorrect. Like an Izod impact test, even the Charpy impact test requires a pendulum/ hammer for the experiment. It is used to cause a rupture in the test specimen being tested."
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "It is a requirement for a ___________ to undergo the torsion test.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sheet",
            "b) wire",
            "c) steel plate",
            "d) wood"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is a necessary requirement for wires to undergo torsion test. There are different types of tests available for different kinds of a specimen like bending test, hardness test, hydrostatic test and crushing test."
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "“Torsion” is defined as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) compressive force",
            "b) type of friction",
            "c) twisting",
            "d) object at rest"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Torsion is defined as the twisting of a specimen caused by a certain amount of torque. Compressive forces are forces that are applied to an object that results in the specimen getting compacted."
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "In a torsion test, if the wire that has to be tested has a diameter of more than 0.333 inches, the specimen needs to have a minimum length of ________ inches.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 33",
            "c) 0.0966",
            "d) 26"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The minimum length required for the specimen is ten inches if the wire being tested has a diameter of more the 0.333 inches in the torsion test. The length requirements vary depending on the diameter of the wire."
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "The setup of a torsion test involves two clamps having a distance of _________ inches between them.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 18",
            "c) 26",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the experimental setup of the torsion test, there are two clamps present. The two clamps secure the wire in between them. The distance between the two camps in the machine is eight inches."
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "In the torsion test, there are two clamps. The clamps are _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) both fixed",
            "b) one fixed one rotating",
            "c) both rotating",
            "d) both joined permanently"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are two clamps present in the experimental set up of the torsion test. One of the clamps is fixed while the other one is rotatable. In the experiment, the rotatable clamp is moved at a certain speed."
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "What is the maximum speed up to which the clamp can be rotated in a torsion test?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 120rpm",
            "b) 2rpm",
            "c) -26rpm",
            "d) 60rpm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The torsion test experimental set up contains two clamps. One is rotatable and the other fixed. The rotatable clamp is moved at a rate of 60rpm (rotations per minute) at maximum. This is because exceeding that speed might cause heating."
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "If a wire that has a diameter of less than 0.033 inches has to undergo a torsion test, the length of the specimen being used must be _________ inches.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 100",
            "c) 30",
            "d) 8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This statement is not true. In the torsion test, steps are taken to ensure that kinking does not occur. The specimen is subjected to the required amount of tension so that kinking does not occur to affect the experiment."
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Options": [
            "9. Tensile stress can be obtained through rotations per minute using the following formula –",
            "= \\(\\frac{rpm×diameter}{2×wall\\, thickness}\\) ",
            "a) True",
            "b) False"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The length required for a specimen of diameter less than 0.033 inches in the torsion test is 30 inches. The length required for the wire being used in this experiment depends on the diameter of the specimen."
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "Torsional strength is the _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) capacity of a material to withstand the twisting load",
            "b) ability to apply force",
            "c) gravitational attraction",
            "d) electrical force"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The equation given above is incorrect. The correct equation is the one that denotes the relationship between tensile strength and internal hydrostatic pressure and is used in the hydrostatic test. It is given as –\ntensile stress = \\(\\frac{internal \\,hydrostatic\\, pressure×diameter}{2×wall\\, thickness}\\)."
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "What is fatigue stress?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The stress endured by an observer",
            "b) Stress divided by strain and multiplied by conductivity",
            "c) The amount of stress, a material can tolerate repeatedly without failure",
            "d) The stress endured perpendicular to the observer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The fatigue stress of a material is the stress it can tolerate several times, without resulting in any failure. Each material has that fatigue stress and if it is crossed it is unsafe to load the material frequently."
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "The amount of test cycles required to find out the fatigue stress of hard steels is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10,000,000",
            "b) 2600",
            "c) 26",
            "d) 2,000,000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The statement is not true. It is not at all easy to determine the fatigue stress of a material. In fact, it is so difficult and consuming that there are lots of materials whose fatigue strength has not been found."
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a fatigue-testing apparatus?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rotating-beam tests",
            "b) Load test",
            "c) Fixed load test",
            "d) Rotating wing test"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Performing a fatigue test on a material is a very difficult task. The amount of test cycles required to be performed on hard steels is 2,000,000. For soft steels, the number of cycles required is 10,000,000."
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "The amount of test cycles required to find out the fatigue stress of hard aluminium alloys is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 64,000,900,000",
            "b) 500,000,000",
            "c) 3000",
            "d) 27"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are several different types of fatigue testing apparatus available to test materials or specimen. But the most widely used apparatus is rotating-beam tests also called as rotating-cantilever tests."
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "What is the typical speed of rotation in a normal speed fatigue testing machine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2000 rpm",
            "b) 20 rpm",
            "c) 26,000 rpm",
            "d) 14,000 rpm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A huge number of test cycles are required to determine the fatigue strength of a material. The number of cycles required for aluminium alloys is 500,000,000. It is the same for magnesium alloys as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "What is the diameter of a typical specimen used in fatigue testing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2000 inches",
            "b) 0.0005 inches",
            "c) 1 inch",
            "d) 26 inches"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The speed of rotation of fatigue testing machines is different for different machines. But, the typical speed is usually of the order of 2000 rpm. For machines that are high speed, it can be 12,000 rpm."
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "The specimen of fatigue testing must not have ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Uniform cross-section",
            "b) Metal",
            "c) Certain colours",
            "d) Notches and holes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Specimen of fatigue tests are typically rolled or forged bar stock. The are one inch in diameter. They can vary depending on the requirements and the material being tested to determine fatigue strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "Corrosion of materials results in ___________ of fatigue limit.",
        "Options": [
            "a) reduction",
            "b) increment",
            "c) double",
            "d) satisfaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: It is necessary that the specimen being tested to determine fatigue strength not have notches and holes in it. The specimen is usually cylindrical rods that do not contain any of the above defects."
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "The fatigue limit of a specimen is ___________ of its fatigue range.",
        "Options": [
            "a) triple",
            "b) double",
            "c) half",
            "d) exactly the same"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Corrosion of a material is not a desirable quality. This is because even a small amount of it can cause a reduction of fatigue limit. Even flaws like lack of uniform cross-section in the specimen can have the same effect."
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "The fatigue limit of steel is around ____ times the ultimate tensile strength.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.3",
            "b) 5",
            "c) 3",
            "d) 0.5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This statement is not true. Materials that have been subjected to heat-treatment have higher tensile strengths, (not lower) compared to materials that are annealed. They also have higher fatigue limits."
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "Which of the following are standard inspection methods of aircraft materials?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Radiography and fatigue test",
            "b) Magnaflux and bending inspection",
            "c) Radiography and magnaflux inspection",
            "d) Fatigue and bending inspection"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is materials being used in aircraft construction that should not experience failure while usage. Hence, it is crucial for the materials to undergo inspection to detect any cracks or defects. There are two standard inspection methods, they are radiography and magnaflux inspection."
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a non-destructive way of inspecting materials?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fatigue",
            "b) Radiography",
            "c) Welding",
            "d) Bending"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Non-destructive testing way of materials refers to a process of inspection where the material is not destroyed or harmed in any way. Radiography is a non-destructive way of inspecting materials."
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "When radiographs are produced to detect defects, they show up as ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) tubes",
            "b) dark spots",
            "c) invisible spots",
            "d) light spots"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Radiography is a non-destructive method of inspecting materials. It is performed by passing either X-rays or gamma-rays through the material being tested. Defects or cracks are obtained in the picture in the form of light spots."
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "What wavelengths are classified as X-rays?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10-6 to 10-25 cm",
            "b) 10-6 to 10-9 cm",
            "c) 10-2 to 10-9 cm",
            "d) 25 to 15cm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Different types of rays are classified based on their respective wavelengths. The wavelength bracket in which the rays are considered to fit the category of X-rays is from 10-6 to 10-9 centimeters."
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "X-rays can be used to inspect materials of steel up to a thickness of __________ inches.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3",
            "b) 15",
            "c) 0.3",
            "d) 26"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: X-rays can be used to inspect materials made up of steel sufficiently up to a thickness of three inches. If the material being inspected is not as dense as steel, it can also be tested for a higher thickness value."
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "Gammagraphs are obtained by passing __________ through a material.",
        "Options": [
            "a) visible rays",
            "b) uv rays",
            "c) gamma-rays",
            "d) x-rays"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Gammagraphs are a type of radiographs. Hence, they are non-destructive in nature. They are obtained by passing gamma-rays through a material. Radiographs and Gammagraphs are also called shadow pictures."
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "Gamma-rays are rays that have a wavelength of around ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10-11",
            "b) 26",
            "c) 10-2",
            "d) 10-22"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Rays like gamma-rays, X-rays are classified based on their wavelengths. The wavelength bracket in which the rays are considered to fit the category of gamma-rays is around 10-11 centimeters."
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "Gamma-rays are acquired from ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Radiograph",
            "b) X-ray",
            "c) U.V",
            "d) Radium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Gamma-rays are acquired from radium. It is typically in radium sulphate form. Gamma-rays are rays having a wavelength of around 10-11  centimeters. It takes radium 1580 years to decay to one-half it’s original strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "Gammagraphs of steel that is as thick as ___________ inches can be acquired.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4",
            "b) 31",
            "c) 8",
            "d) 15"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Gammagraphs of steel parts or materials as thick as eight inches can also be acquired. This is higher compared to radiographs with X-rays that can be used for steel as thick as only three inches."
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "One of the disadvantages of radiography is that it is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) destructive",
            "b) faster",
            "c) temporary record",
            "d) time-consuming"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This statement is incorrect. X-rays are not stronger compared to gamma-rays. In fact, the contrary is true. X-rays are weak compared to gamma-rays, due to which gamma-rays can be used to inspect materials of greater thickness."
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "___________ is an inspection method for magnetic objects",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fatigue",
            "b) Magnaflux",
            "c) Gammagraphs",
            "d) Bending"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are a lot of advantages and disadvantages of standard inspection methods. When it comes to radiography, one of the disadvantages is that it can be time-consuming. It also needs photography."
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "X-rays being used to produce radiographs are called ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Radiographs",
            "b) Magnaflux",
            "c) Exographs",
            "d) Gammagraphs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is true. Fluoroscopy is a method of non-destructive inspection that has been developed after radiography. It requires a higher voltage compared to radiography to perform."
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "Which of the following can the inspection process ‘magnaflu’ not detect?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Laps",
            "b) Cracks",
            "c) Seams",
            "d) Color"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Magnaflux is a magnetic inspection method used to detect defects and non-metallic quantities in a magnetic material. It can detect cracks, seams etc. but cannot detect colour of the specimen."
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "In which direction should the magnetic flux be induced on the specimen?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Upper",
            "b) Lower",
            "c) All directions",
            "d) North"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is important in the magnaflux inspection method that the lines of force (magnetic) go through the defect perpendicularly. For this reason, since the location of defects is not know, it should be induced in all directions."
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a way to magnetize a specimen?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Angular magnetization",
            "b) Momentum magnetization",
            "c) Circular magnetization",
            "d) Zero magnetization"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: There are two ways in which a specimen in the magnaflux process can be magnetized. Circular magnetization and bipolar magnetization. Angular magnetization does not exist in this process."
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "_____________ can be put on the specimen in the form of magnetic powder.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Uranium",
            "b) Black iron oxide",
            "c) Charred wood",
            "d) Chromium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is true. The magnaflux method also detects the location of flaws. This is because the powder on the specimen is disturbed as magnetic lines of force are also disturbed in the location of the flaws."
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "What is the continuous method of magnaflux inspection method?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The continuous specimen is used",
            "b) Partial current mixing",
            "c) Current is put on throughout the process",
            "d) Non-existent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is necessary to put a substance on the specimen that can indicate the presence of flaws on it. Black iron oxide or ferroso ferric oxide is generally used as magnetic powder. They can be applied either wet or dry."
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "Before sending the material that is being inspected to construct an aircraft, it has to be ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) washed",
            "b) compressed",
            "c) liquefied",
            "d) demagnetized"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The continuous method of magnaflux involves inducing both circular and longitudinal current at the same time and running it throughout the entire process. This is known to give good results."
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "How far must the specimen be withdrawn with respect to the coil in demagnetization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 00.7 inches",
            "b) 26 inches",
            "c) 18 inches",
            "d) 4 inches"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. There are three ways in which the magnaflux inspection method is carried out. Circular magnetization, bipolar magnetization and the continuous method."
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "One of the methods used to demagnetize a specimen involves keeping the specimen in the coil and slowly decrease the current to ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) double the initial value",
            "b) 0",
            "c) 26.5",
            "d) high"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Some Aircraft materials typically undergo the magnaflux inspection process. After the inspection process is done the parts have to be demagnetized before being used for manufacturing. This is because otherwise, they will interfere with the plane’s compass."
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "The primary commercial source for aluminium is ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) coal",
            "b) bauxite",
            "c) magnetite",
            "d) pyrite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Aluminium can be obtained from several sources. For example, it is found in several clays and rocks. But the primary source for aluminium is bauxite ores. Bauxite contains aluminium and some impurities."
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "Aluminium weighs around __________ of steel.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2 times",
            "b) 1/2",
            "c) 1/3",
            "d) 4 times"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: One of the most important advantages of aluminium is its weight. Aluminium weighs less than steel. But steel is stronger compared to aluminium. Steel weighs almost three times the weight of aluminium."
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "A ____________ process is carried out to get aluminium from the oxide alumina.",
        "Options": [
            "a) electrolytic",
            "b) dynamite",
            "c) chromatography",
            "d) bakelite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium is often found in the ore bauxite. But, it is found along with a lot of impurities. Therefore, a chemical process purifies it to alumina after which it is subjected to an electrolytic process."
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "Which of the following are shapes used in the manufacturing of an aircraft?",
        "Options": [
            "a) X-section",
            "b) U-section and Z-section",
            "c) X-section and Z-section",
            "d) U-section"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are several shapes required to manufacture the structure of an aircraft. Some of the shapes are Z-section, U-section, bars, sheets and tubing. X-section is not a shape used in the construction of an aircraft."
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "The aluminium association has a designation system for aluminium alloys which are denoted by __________ digits.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 23",
            "b) 2",
            "c) 9",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The aluminium association has a designation system for aluminium alloys that are denoted by four digits. The four digits of numbers represent different parameters of the material, aluminium alloys."
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "The melting point of aluminium is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 236°c",
            "b) 1085°c",
            "c) 660°c",
            "d) 1510°c"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Aluminium alloys are materials with lots of advantages. They are used extensively in building an aircraft. The structure of the aircraft and wing beams are also manufactured using aluminium alloys. "
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a common property for all aluminium alloys?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Low strength",
            "b) Heat treatable",
            "c) Easy for machining",
            "d) Readily joined be welding"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The melting point of aluminium is 660°c. Aluminium alloys are subjected to different temperatures during heat treatment. The melting point of copper is 1085°c. The melting point of steel is 1510°c."
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "Aluminium is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) non-magnetic",
            "b) ductile",
            "c) magnetic",
            "d) non-magnetic and ductile"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium alloys are good materials to use in the aerospace industry. They are heat treatable, can readily be joined by welding, soldering and are easy to machine. They also have high strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an aluminium alloy?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Al-Si",
            "b) Al-Zn",
            "c) Al-Mn",
            "d) Al-U"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Aluminium is a soft material. It is silvery-white in colour. It has a melting point of around 660°c. It is also both non-magnetic and ductile in nature. The atomic number of the element aluminium is 13."
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "Why has the aluminium association established a system of designating aluminium alloys?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To create employment",
            "b) To remove confusion",
            "c) To encourage research",
            "d) To ensure availability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Aluminium alloys are alloys where aluminium is present in a higher amount. Aluminium alloys can be made with aluminium and zinc, aluminium and manganese, aluminium and silicon, etc. Uranium is a radioactive material."
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "The final two digits in the nomenclature of aluminium alloys represent aluminium __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) impurity",
            "b) group",
            "c) purity",
            "d) strength"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The aluminium association has made this system to remove confusion. The confusion was caused due to companies having different numbering systems for aluminium materials of similar chemical composition."
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "Pitting of the surface is a kind of aluminium alloy __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) corrosion",
            "b) annealing",
            "c) strength",
            "d) manufacturing method"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The nomenclature of aluminium alloys was made by the aluminium association to avoid confusion. It consists of 4 digits that represent various parameters. The last two digits indicate aluminium purity."
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "Aluminium alloys can be categorized into Cast and ___________ alloys.",
        "Options": [
            "a) extrusions",
            "b) heat treatable",
            "c) non-heat treatable",
            "d) wrought"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One of the most important factors to consider while dealing with materials is corrosion. Aluminium alloys can be painted with a coating to avoid it. Pitting of the surface is corrosion that affects the surface due to the existence of moisture. "
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a chemical process used to extract aluminium?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Osmosis",
            "b) Radiography",
            "c) Heliography",
            "d) Pyrometallurgy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Aluminium is obtained through ores like bauxite. To extract aluminium several chemical methods and processes are applied. Pyrometallurgy is a chemical process that involves extracting metals in the presence of high temperatures."
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "Recycling of aluminium requires _________ of energy to make new aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.5%",
            "b) 25%",
            "c) 5%",
            "d) 50%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Aluminium can be absolutely recycled. In any of its forms for example tins, cans, etc. it can be taken to a plant where it is treated. In this process, only five percent of energy is required to manufacture new aluminium."
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "Hydrometallurgy is the process of extracting __________ from ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) flight parts, metals",
            "b) metals, flight parts",
            "c) metals, ores",
            "d) ores, metals"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Hydrometallurgy is a chemical process that can be used in the extraction of aluminium. It is a process that involves extracting metals from ores by preparing and using an aqueous solution in the process."
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "Aluminium ores can be obtained in large amounts from which of the following countries?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Africa, Greenland",
            "b) Africa, Australia",
            "c) Greenland",
            "d) Australia"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium can be extracted using several chemical and electrical processes. Electrometallurgy is one such process that involves the extraction of aluminium by using an electrical discharge in the process."
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "The Hall-Heroult process is used for ___________ aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) breaking",
            "b) distributing",
            "c) smelting",
            "d) mixing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Aluminium is obtained through ores, typically bauxite. It is present in several countries like Greece, the United States, France, India and China. The ore bauxite is present abundantly in Africa and Australia."
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "The Hall-Heroult process is carried out at a temperature of __________ industrially.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 940-980°C",
            "b) 200-300°C",
            "c) 10,000-50,000°C",
            "d) 50-70°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Hall-Heroult process is used in the smelting of aluminium. Smelting refers to the extraction of metal using heat. Several metals can be extracted using this process, including aluminium, silver, copper, iron, etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "The Hall-Heroult process produces around _______ pure aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100%",
            "b) 20%",
            "c) 98%",
            "d) 4%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Hall-Heroult process is an extraction process of metals that involves the usage of heat. For this process, when it is being carried out industrially for a large quantity, the temperature at which it is done is between 940-980°C."
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "The voltage in the Hall-Heroult process is around __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2-9 V",
            "b) 15.5-16.5 V",
            "c) 26-45 V",
            "d) 6-8 V"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Molten cryolite is used in the Hall-Heroult process of extraction of aluminium.  It is not a common mineral and is usually colourless or white. It is of brittle tenacity."
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "_______ percent of earth’s crust is aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3%",
            "b) 25%",
            "c) 60%",
            "d) 7%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Around seven percent of the earth’s crust is aluminium. Aluminium is primarily found in its ore bauxite. It is also found in several rocks, clays and soils. Aluminium is finally obtained after various types of processing."
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "Aluminium is __________ and __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) non-hygienic, toxic",
            "b) toxic, hygienic",
            "c) non-toxic, hygienic",
            "d) non-hygienic, non-toxic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Aluminium is a non-toxic and hygienic material. This is the reason why it is widely used in several industries around the world without any drastic or negative repercussions. It is one of its advantageous properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "Aluminum has a ____________ strength to weight ratio.",
        "Options": [
            "a) moderate",
            "b) low",
            "c) high",
            "d) infinite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Aluminium has a high strength to weight ratio. Especially compared to other strong metals like iron. This gives an advantage in industries where it is desirable to have a very high strength to weight ratio."
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "The metal aluminium can be ___________ to obtain strength.",
        "Options": [
            "a) heat-treated",
            "b) nullified",
            "c) softened",
            "d) non-heat treated"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One of the properties of aluminium that is widely applicable is the ability to be heat treated. Aluminium is subjected to heat treatment to increase its performance characteristics as it becomes stronger."
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "In the aircraft industry, aluminium is ______ used.",
        "Options": [
            "a) moderately",
            "b) widely",
            "c) not often",
            "d) hardly"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Aluminium is widely used in the aircraft industry. It is mainly used in the form of alloys with other elements. One of the primary reasons for its usage is the high strength to weight ratio of aluminium."
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "It is ___________ to recycle aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) impossible",
            "b) difficult",
            "c) easy",
            "d) rarely possible"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is easy to recycle aluminium. Recycling of aluminium requires around five percent of energy to make new aluminium. Recycled aluminium is frequently used in several industries across the world."
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an advantageous property of aluminium?",
        "Options": [
            "a) High modulus of elasticity",
            "b) High weight",
            "c) High fuel consumption",
            "d) High payload capacity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium can also be used in the making of medicines in the medical field. One such example for human beings is its usage in medicines that deal with kidney failures in the human body."
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "Aluminium is suitable for the _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) aircraft industry",
            "b) transportation industry",
            "c) aircraft industry and transportation industry",
            "d) jewel industry"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Aluminium has several advantages. One of its advantages is its high payload capacity. High weight is typically not considered an advantage in industries like aerospace. Aluminium is known to be a lightweight material compared to materials like iron."
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "Aluminium is ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) brittle",
            "b) ductile",
            "c) magnetic",
            "d) brownish-red"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Aluminium is suitable for several industries, which also include the aircraft industry and the transportation industry. It is also used for cosmetic products, deodorants, household appliances and several other fields."
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "One of the most widely recycled products are ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) aluminium cosmetics",
            "b) aluminium cans",
            "c) aluminium discs",
            "d) welding aluminium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Aluminium is a ductile material. It is not a brittle material. It is also silver-white in colour and is a non-magnetic substance. Its melting point is 660 degrees Celsius and the atomic number is thirteen."
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "It is easy to manufacture components/products using aluminium because of ____________ cutting speed.",
        "Options": [
            "a) high",
            "b) even",
            "c) moderate",
            "d) smooth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: One of the most widely recycled products in the world is aluminium cans. This is because aluminium is used packaging several items due to its advantageous properties. Cosmetics also contain some aluminium in them."
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "One of the advantages of aluminium compared to steel is ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) lower production cost",
            "b) higher-strength",
            "c) higher weight",
            "d) low corrosion"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium is known to have a high cutting speed. This makes it easier to manufacture components or products. Aluminium is also known for being a soft material. It is also suitable for welding."
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "________ of all the food products in the world are packaged using aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1/5",
            "b) 1/3",
            "c) 1/2",
            "d) 2/3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Aluminium creates a natural layer around itself that protects it from corrosion. Steel has a higher strength and weight when compared to aluminium. Aluminium also has a higher production and manufacturing cost."
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "Titanium is __________ in color.",
        "Options": [
            "a) red",
            "b) white",
            "c) reddish-brown",
            "d) silvery-white"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The element titanium is typically silvery-white in color. It is a metallic element that has a high strength to weight ratio. It is also known to be a lustrous metal with excellent strength and hardness."
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "Titanium has __________ density.",
        "Options": [
            "a) low",
            "b) high",
            "c) moderate",
            "d) zero"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Titanium is a metallic element that has low density. It is one of the properties of the material. Density refers to the ratio of the mass to the volume of the material. It indicates certain properties of a material."
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "The atomic number for titanium is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 26",
            "b) 196",
            "c) 22",
            "d) 13"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The atomic number of titanium is sixteen. The atomic number of aluminium is thirteen. The atomic number of steels is twenty-six. There is no possibility of having 196 as an atomic number as there are only 118 elements."
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "The melting point of titanium is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3272°F",
            "b) 1220°F",
            "c) 2795°F",
            "d) 3272°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The melting point of titanium is 3272°F. It is much higher compared to the melting point of other metals. For example, the melting point of aluminium is 1220°F. The melting point of steel is 2500°F."
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "Titanium consists of about _________ of the earth’s crust.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 27.7%",
            "b) 0.57%",
            "c) 2.34%",
            "d) 5%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Titanium consists of around 0.57% of the earth’s crust. It is the ninth most abundantly found material. Silicone is found in higher quantities compared to titanium in the earth’s crust which is around 27.7%."
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "In which of the following countries are titanium abundantly found in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ukraine",
            "b) Greenland",
            "c) Antarctica",
            "d) Canada, Ukraine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Titanium is found in several locations across the world because it is the ninth most abundantly found material in the earth’s crust. It is found mostly in Canada, Australia, Ukraine and North America."
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "Titanium will not be found in a __________ state.",
        "Options": [
            "a) uncombined",
            "b) sunny",
            "c) combined",
            "d) typical"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Titanium is a very highly reactive material in slightly elevated temperatures. This is the reason why it has not been found in an uncombined state and has a strong bond with other elements chemically."
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "The primary ores of titanium are _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) rutile, sulphur",
            "b) ilmenite, bauxite",
            "c) bauxite, rutile",
            "d) rutile, ilmenite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  Titanium ores are distributed across the globe and the metal is very abundant in nature. Titanium ores mostly contain its dioxide. The primary ores of titanium are the ores routine and ilmenite."
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "The atomic weight of titanium is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 55.84g",
            "b) 26.97g",
            "c) 47.9g",
            "d) 35.5g"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The atomic weight of titanium is 47.9 grams. It is higher compared to some metals like aluminium as it has a weight of 26.97 grams and is lighter than metals like steel that have an atomic weight of 55.84 grams."
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "Chloride process involves separation of titanium from its ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) oxidizers",
            "b) shores",
            "c) reactants",
            "d) ores"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The chloride process is used to extract titanium products from an ore. Some titanium ores are rutile, ilmenite, leucoxene and scheelite. These titanium ores can be found in places like Australia, China, New Zealand etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "Which of the following is one of the main production unit of the chloride process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ore stage",
            "b) Coke stage",
            "c) Oxidation",
            "d) Off gas treatment"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the chloride process, there are main production units and auxiliary production units. Oxidation is one of the main production units. Here, the oxidizing agent for the oxidation process is molecular oxygen."
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an auxiliary production unit of the chloride process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Chlorination",
            "b) Purification",
            "c) Dust treatment",
            "d) Condensation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The units in the chloride process of extraction from ores can roughly be divided into main production unit and auxiliary production unit. Both are vital for this process. Dust treatment is an auxiliary production unit."
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "The linear coefficient of thermal expansion of titanium is ___________ /°F.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6.1×106",
            "b) 9.5×106",
            "c) 4.3×106",
            "d) 12.7×106"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. It is possible for titanium to be alloyed with different elements and it is often done frequently. This includes alloying with several elements like vanadium, molybdenum, aluminium etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "Titanium is typically corrosion _________ in normal environments.",
        "Options": [
            "a) resistant",
            "b) positive",
            "c) prone",
            "d) familiar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Zirconium is a different element. It has an atomic number of 40 and is a lustrous element. It resembles titanium in some character traits but is not completely identical to it."
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "In the process of chlorination, one of the reaction is oxygen combining with carbon to form __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) carbon trioxide",
            "b) chlorine oxide",
            "c) sulphate",
            "d) carbon dioxide"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The linear coefficient of thermal expansion of titanium is 4.3×106/°F. The linear coefficient of thermal expansion of other elements like aluminium is 12.7×106/°F and that of stainless steel is 9.5×106/°F."
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "The purity of the product produced in the chloride reaction is around ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 81%",
            "b) 65%",
            "c) 99%",
            "d) 43%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One of the benefits of the element titanium is its great corrosion-resistant property in a normal environment. However, in the presence of concentrated acids, titanium experiences corrosion. "
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "Gas ___________ use an overwhelming amount of titanium produced in the world.",
        "Options": [
            "a) chambers",
            "b) turbines",
            "c) molecules",
            "d) manure"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the chloride process, there is involvement of chlorine, titanium and coke. Here when oxygen combines with carbon forms carbon dioxide. There are also other elements formed in the reaction."
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "Titanium alloys can be forged ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) moderately",
            "b) with great difficulty",
            "c) unnecessarily",
            "d) easily"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Titanium alloys can be forged easily. This is possible if in the process of forging it, certain design rules are followed on the particular titanium alloy being done. These precautions are necessary."
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "Titanium has applications in the __________ industries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) aerospace",
            "b) chemical",
            "c) aerospace and chemical",
            "d) chemical and stock"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Titanium has applications in several industries due to its nature. It has properties and characteristics that can be used in Industries like both the aerospace industry and the chemical industry."
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "Titanium alloys (body centred cubic) ___________ heat treatment for high strength.",
        "Options": [
            "a) require",
            "b) are made by",
            "c) do not require",
            "d) preceded"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: It is possible for the element titanium to exist in two crystal forms. Hexagonal close-packed structure and body – centred cubic structure. Each of these poses certain qualities and responses to heat treatment. Body centred cubic structure do not require them for strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "Hydrogen is __________ for titanium sheets.",
        "Options": [
            "a) beneficial",
            "b) required",
            "c) harmful",
            "d) provided"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. The element titanium can be used extensively in the medical industry. It is specifically used in implants for the human body. It is used for knee and hip implants."
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "___________ increases the transformation temperature of titanium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nitrogen",
            "b) Tantalum",
            "c) Vanadium",
            "d) Columbium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Titanium alloys, particularly the body-centred cubic alloys when compared to other types of materials tend to have a relatively high density. This is an advantageous property."
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "___________ reduces the transformation temperature of titanium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Carbon",
            "b) Aluminium",
            "c) Oxygen",
            "d) Molybdenum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Hydrogen is very harmful for titanium or titanium sheets. It is not beneficial. It contaminates titanium during processes like heating. Several precautions like oxidizing atmospheres are used."
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "The specific heat of titanium is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.23 Cal./gm./°C",
            "b) 0.12 Cal./gm./°C",
            "c) 0.129 Cal./gm./°C",
            "d) 5.6 Cal./gm./°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The transformation temperature of an element is the temperature that increases or decreases the transformation point of the element. Adding nitrogen increases the transformation temperature of the resulting element."
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "Combined titanium alloys are relatively ___________ to produce in quantity.",
        "Options": [
            "a) moderate",
            "b) easy",
            "c) complicated",
            "d) high"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Adding molybdenum reduces the transformation temperature of titanium. The transformation point or the point when its crystal structure changes is linked to transformation temperature. The transformation temperature can be changed by adding certain elements."
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": "The density of titanium is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7.92 gm. per c.c",
            "b) 4.5 gm. per c.c",
            "c) 13.6 gm. per c.c",
            "d) 2.80 gm. per c.c"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A element can be defined or described by certain properties like physical properties. The physical properties of an element include melting point, specific heat, density, linear coefficient of thermal expansion and specific heat."
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": "Compared to steel, titanium alloys are more __________ to deformation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bent",
            "b) complying",
            "c) prone",
            "d) resistant"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Combined titanium alloys are relatively easy to produce in high quantities. They are also easier for forging, rolling and forming compared to other alloys. These factors are advantageous properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "Which of the following aircraft parts are manufactured using a high amount of titanium?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aircraft engines, wing structure, landing gear components",
            "b) Landing gear components, wheels, gas turbines",
            "c) Hydraulic tubes, slings, wheels",
            "d) Aircraft engines, landing gear components"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Density is one of the factors that describe the physical property of an element or a material. The density of titanium is 4.5 gm. per c.c. The density of aluminium is 2.8 gm. per c.c and stainless steel is 7.92 gm. per c.c."
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "The F-22 aircraft is made of approximately around ___ % titanium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15",
            "b) 69",
            "c) 39",
            "d) 82"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Titanium alloys are more resistant to deformation compared to steel. This results in having to take certain precautionary measures while forging titanium alloys. The element titanium also differs in other properties compared to other metals."
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": "Which of the following components can be made using titanium?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Wheelchairs",
            "b) Golf clubs, bicycles",
            "c) Sunscreen, balloons",
            "d) Wheelchairs, golf clubs, bicycles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Titanium can be used in several industries. Some of the specific components that use titanium in their manufacturing process are aircraft engines, wing structure, gas turbines, hydraulic tubes and landing gear components."
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "The melting point of steel is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1220°F",
            "b) 670°F",
            "c) 3272°F",
            "d) 2500°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The melting point of steel is usually around 2500° Fahrenheit. The melting points of materials differ. For example, the melting point of aluminium is 1220°F and that of titanium is around 3272°F."
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "Steel is a material that is primarily made with __________ and __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) titanium, carbon",
            "b) chromium, iron",
            "c) iron, carbon",
            "d) iron, titanium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Steel is a material that is made by combining several metals to obtain several types of physical characteristics. Primarily, both iron and carbon are important for this process along with other elements in minute quantities."
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "___________ is a harmful property in the material.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Carbon",
            "b) Silicon",
            "c) Sulphur",
            "d) Manganese"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: There are certain elements that are good to metal steel while there are some elements that are not good for it. Sulphur is an element that is harmful and is best kept in low quantities. So it is phosphorous."
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "It is possible to make a ____________ number of steels.",
        "Options": [
            "a) huge",
            "b) certain",
            "c) specified",
            "d) couple of"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Steel is basically a combination of different metals that result in different types of physical characteristics. It is possible to make an infinite number of steels because iron combines with a huge number of elements."
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Iron combines easily with ___________ to make iron carbide.",
        "Options": [
            "a) manganese",
            "b) carbon",
            "c) steel",
            "d) chromium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Iron combines easily with carbon and results in iron carbide. It is also known as cementite. The greater the amount of carbon, the greater the amount of ultimate strength and hardness. But, ductility decreases."
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "Steels that are resistant to corrosion have high amounts of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) manganese",
            "b) iron",
            "c) chromium",
            "d) carbon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The steels that are resistant to corrosion are made with high amounts of chromium. They also tend to be non-magnetic in nature with a few exceptions. Chromium can also be combined with other metals to form alloys."
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "Around ___________ types of steels are used in constructing an aircraft.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 13",
            "c) 59",
            "d) 20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is true. In order to properly classify and gauge the composition of the substance, this numerical system can be useful. It contains numbers and alphabets that represent different qualities."
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "In steel, manganese is helpful in __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) heating",
            "b) shine",
            "c) deoxidize",
            "d) volume"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Steels are widely used in the aerospace industry and in particular the construction of aircraft. They are used in making brace struts, landing gear, wings etc. Around 20 types of steels are used."
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "An extra quantity of more than ___ % of manganese will heighten brittleness of the metal.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 1",
            "c) 44",
            "d) 13"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Manganese is a useful element for steel. It particularly helps in deoxidizing and desulphurizing the material. This makes the metal tough. It also helps in the forging process of metal steel."
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "Steels made of nickel typically contain _______ to _____ % of nickel.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 23 to 56",
            "b) 10 to 20",
            "c) 8 to 19",
            "d) 3 to 5"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: An extra quantity that is not required of more than one percent can make the material extra brittle. Manganese is advantageous when added in the right amount. It is also none magnetic in nature."
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "The density of stainless steel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4.5 gm. Per c.c",
            "b) 6.8 gm. Per c.c",
            "c) 2.8 gm. Per c.c",
            "d) 7.92 gm. Per c.c"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Density is the ratio of mass to volume of a substance or object. The density of stainless steel is around 7.92 gm. Per c.c. 4.5 gm. Per c.c is the density of titanium and 2.8 gm. Per c.c is the density of aluminium."
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "The atomic number of stainless steels is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 13",
            "b) 22",
            "c) 26",
            "d) 3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The atomic number indicated the number of protons in the nucleus of an atom. The atomic number of stainless steels is twenty-six. The atomic number of aluminium is thirteen and that of titanium is twenty-two."
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "The atomic weight of stainless steel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 60",
            "b) 26.97",
            "c) 55.84",
            "d) 47.9"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The atomic weight or atomic mass of stainless steel is typically 55.84. This is because while steel or stainless steel is not an element, it consists primarily of iron. Hence, its atomic mass is considered 55.84 u."
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "___________ steel is required when high hardness is desired and ductility is not crucial.",
        "Options": [
            "a) High-carbon steel",
            "b) Low-carbon steel",
            "c) Medium-carbon steel",
            "d) Wrought iron"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Different types of steel, or steel that differs in its components and concentration of carbon show different properties. High-carbon steel is required when ductility is not crucial but hardness is important."
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "Manganese has a property known as penetration ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) softness",
            "b) hardness",
            "c) medium",
            "d) ductility"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Manganese has a property commonly known as penetration hardness. This is when the manganese is subjected to heat treatment of large sections and hardness penetrates to the core instead of being limited to the surface."
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "The amount of carbon present in high carbon steel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.10% to 0.30%",
            "b) 2.2% to 4.5%",
            "c) 0.70% to 2.2%",
            "d) 12% to 13%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The amount of carbon present in steel differs. They are classified as high carbon steels, low carbon steels, medium carbon steels and wrought iron and cast iron. High carbon steel has 0.70% to 2.2% of carbon."
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "Medium carbon steels are preferred when both ___________ strength and __________ is necessary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) no, brittle nature",
            "b) good, brittle nature",
            "c) no, ductility",
            "d) good, ductility"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. “Red hardness” of tungsten steels is an advantageous property. It means that this tungsten chromium steel used in tools when heated to dull redness tends to keep its cutting edge."
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "__________ element is responsible for “cold shortness”.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Manganese",
            "b) Carbon",
            "c) Phosphorus",
            "d) Sulphur"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Steels that contain different levels of carbon exhibit different properties and each type is used for specific applications. Medium carbon steels are used when both good strength and ductility are necessary."
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "Chromium has a __________ melting point.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Low",
            "b) High",
            "c) Medium",
            "d) Average"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The element phosphorus is the cause of the phenomenon “cold shortness” or brittleness. This happens when metal is cold.  Phosphorus is an undesirable element in steels. It should not be present in more than 0.05% in quantity."
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "Molybdenum decreases the ___________ of material.",
        "Options": [
            "a) elastic limit",
            "b) grain size",
            "c) homogeneity",
            "d) impact value"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Chromium is an element that has a high melting point. It is a hard grey metal. It is a desirable element as it gives strength, magnetic quality, wear resistance, hardness and corrosion resistance."
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Question": "Tools that are made of tungsten-chromium contain _____ of tungsten.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2% to 4%",
            "b) 5% to 10%",
            "c) 20% to 25%",
            "d) 14% to 18%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Molybdenum is a very productive element in steel. It decreases the grain size. It also increases the homogeneity, elastic limit and impact value. Steels containing molybdenum also exhibit an increase in air-hardening properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "The steel being used in the construction of aircraft must be ___________ to fabricate.",
        "Options": [
            "a) moderate",
            "b) difficult",
            "c) impossible",
            "d) easy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are several requirements that have to be checked for materials that have to be used in aircraft construction, like mechanical properties. One of the properties is the ease of fabrication of the material."
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "The amount of carbon present in low carbon steels is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5% to 7%",
            "b) 0.70% to 2.2%",
            "c) 0.10% to 0.30%",
            "d) 0.6% to 0.8%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Carbon is an extremely significant material/substance in steel.  There are different types of steel based on the amount of carbon present. Low carbon steels have a carbon content of 0.10% to 0.30%. High carbon steel has 0.70% to 2.2% carbon."
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "The amount of carbon present in wrought iron is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3% to 4%",
            "b) Trace to 0.08%",
            "c) 0.30% to 0.70%",
            "d) 2.2% to 4.5%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. It is not possible for a large amount of sulphur to be present in steel as it is considered to be an undesirable impurity. It has to be present in less than 0.06 percentage."
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "Silico-manganese steels have advantageous __________ resistance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) chromium",
            "b) tensile",
            "c) impact",
            "d) clutch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is true. Chromium is a very advantageous material that gives hardness, strength and corrosion resistance to steel when it is added to it. Combining it with nickel also results in good properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "A material that requires __________ heat-treatment is preferred over a material that requires a ___ of heat-treatment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) less, higher amount",
            "b) a high, lower amount",
            "c) a moderate, lower amount",
            "d) high, no amount"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Iron and steel can be categorized based on the amount of carbon present. Wrought iron contains trace to 0.08% of carbon. Medium carbon steel contains 0.30% to 0.70% of carbon. Cast iron contains 2.2% to 4.5% of carbon."
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "Mild ___________ steel is used for aircraft nuts.",
        "Options": [
            "a) phosphorus",
            "b) nickel",
            "c) silicon",
            "d) carbon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Steel contains a very low amount of silicone. Less than 0.3%. The ductility of metal can increase by the addition of a small quantity of silicon. Silico-manganese steels have an advantageous impact resistance."
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "The steel S.A.E 1025 has an ultimate tensile strength of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12,000 p.s.i",
            "b) 6,000 p.s.i",
            "c) 55,000 p.s.i",
            "d) 22,000 p.s.i"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are several factors that are considered while choosing the metal that has to be used in the construction of components of an aircraft. Materials requiring less heat treatment are typically preferred."
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "As the amount of carbon in steel increases, its ____________ increases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ductility",
            "b) impact resistance",
            "c) hardness",
            "d) weldability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Steels are used in the construction of different components and tools of an aircraft. Mild carbon steel, also called as cold-rolled stock is used to manufacture some standard parts that also includes aircraft nuts."
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Question": "As the amount of carbon in steel increases, its ___________ decreases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) range of heat treatment",
            "b) toughness",
            "c) ultimate strength",
            "d) hardness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The steel S.A.E 1025 is also called mild carbon steel and cold-rolled stock. It has an ultimate tensile strength of 55,000 p.s.i. It is bought cold-rolled for aircraft manufacturing purposes. It develops a higher strength when heat treated."
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "___________ is a special kind of steel that is used exclusively for nitrided components.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nitric",
            "b) Hy-Tuf",
            "c) Austenitic",
            "d) Nitriding steel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Nitriding steel is a type of special steel. It is applied for bushing and gears and is used specifically for nitrided components. It is also known to have good surface hardness along with other advantages."
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "__________ is the name that refers to steel used in high tensile strength. (220,000-240,000 p.s.i)",
        "Options": [
            "a) S.A.E 1103",
            "b) Carburizing",
            "c) Hy-Tuf",
            "d) S.A.E 8375"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Hy-Tuf (trade name) is extensively used in the construction of an aircraft, specifically hooks and landing gear components. These parts require high tensile strength. These steels should be processed with great care."
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "____________ is known as Hadfield’s manganese steel.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6150 steel",
            "b) Hydroxide steel",
            "c) Austenitic manganese steel",
            "d) Nitride manganese steel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Austenitic manganese steel is called Hadfield’s manganese steel. It is a highly tough material. The material is also exceedingly difficult to machine. It also has good resistance to wear."
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "S.A.E 4037 is a ___________ steel that can be used as a substitute for nickel steel in making bolts, pins etc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) hydroxide",
            "b) vanadium",
            "c) molybdenum",
            "d) chromium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: S.A.E 4037 is molybdenum steel. This can be used as a replacement for nickel steel in manufacturing several parts like bolts, pins, terminals and several other kinds of components. It is heated to obtain certain tensile strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "S.A.E 4130 is a ___________ steel that can be typically used in manufacturing parts made of sheet and tubing.",
        "Options": [
            "a) chrome-molybdenum",
            "b) silicon",
            "c) vanadium",
            "d) uranium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. It is necessary for the manufacturing of components of aircraft that materials that are easy to fabricate are used. Steel can be fabricated and it is not very difficult to do so."
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "Steel has a ____________ strength to weight ratio.",
        "Options": [
            "a) extremely low",
            "b) low",
            "c) medium",
            "d) high"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Steel has several advantageous properties. Specifically, when it comes to strength, cost etc. Due to these properties, steel is used in the manufacturing of several structures like bridges, buildings, warehouses etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "Steel is very ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) rarely used",
            "b) costly",
            "c) durable",
            "d) non-moldable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The chrome-molybdenum steel S.A.E 4130 is used in manufacturing aircraft parts that are made of sheet and tubing. It is preferred for its good welding characteristics and it’s reaction to heat treatment."
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "Steel has a __________ fatigue life in comparison to other metals like aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) similar",
            "b) higher",
            "c) no",
            "d) lower"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Steel has a good/high strength to weight ratio. It may not be as good as the metal aluminium, which has a much lower weight but steel has very good strength properties and is stronger compared to several other metals."
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "The atomic number of magnesium is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2",
            "b) 15",
            "c) 5",
            "d) 12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The atomic number of the element magnesium is twelve. The atomic number of an element indicates the number of protons in the nucleus of its atom. Five is the atomic number of boron and two is that of helium."
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "The melting point of magnesium is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1250°",
            "b) 327°",
            "c) 650°C",
            "d) 1668°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The melting point of magnesium is 650° Celsius. The melting point of a solid object indicates the point at which it will melt. The melting point of titanium is 1668° Celsius and that of lead is 327° Celsius."
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "Magnesium alloys are __________ and __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) non-magnetic, non-sparkling",
            "b) magnetic, sparkling",
            "c) non-magnetic, non-sparkling",
            "d) magnetic, non-sparkling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium alloys have a set of physical and chemical properties that describe or denote their characteristics. Magnesium alloys are not magnetic nature. Also, unlike some other elements, they are non-sparkling."
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "Magnesium is frequently alloyed with __________ and _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) aluminium, zinc",
            "b) uranium, aluminium",
            "c) vanadium, zinc",
            "d) zinc, uranium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Alloying an element with other elements is known to produce some advantageous and desired properties that can be used for several industrial and scientific purposes. Magnesium is frequently alloyed with aluminium and zinc."
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "Magnesium is a ___________ metal.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bluish-grey",
            "b) reddish",
            "c) silvery-white",
            "d) yellow"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium is a metal/element that is commonly used in the aircraft industry due to its advantageous properties. It is a silvery-white metal. Lead is a metal that is bluish-grey in colour. Sulphur and chlorine are yellow."
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "Pure magnesium weighs around ___________ of aluminium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 98%",
            "b) 2%",
            "c) 39%",
            "d) 65%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Magnesium is a very beneficial element to use due to its weight. It is a very lightweight metal and weighs around 65% of aluminium. It does not possess a high amount of strength but is used when strength is not the primary factor being considered."
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "The specific gravity of magnesium is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.8",
            "b) 7.9",
            "c) 2.7",
            "d) 13.8"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The specific gravity of an object refers to the ratio of the density of that object to the density of a reference object. The specific gravity of magnesium is 1.8. The specific gravity of aluminium is 2.7 and steel is 7.9."
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "Which of the following are frequently found impurities in magnesium alloys?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Copper, vanadium",
            "b) Aluminium, nickel",
            "c) Nickel, iron",
            "d) Nickel, Indium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Magnesium is not frequently found in its natural state, in fact, it is never found in its natural state. It is found in ores and has to be processed to obtain pure magnesium."
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "Magnesium is convenient to use when ____________ thickness is required.",
        "Options": [
            "a) lateral",
            "b) maximum",
            "c) high",
            "d) minimum"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Magnesium is used in making several components across industries in the world. Considering its physical and chemical properties, it should be used when strength is not the primary criteria and minimum thickness is required."
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "Magnesium alloys are obtainable in the form of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) permanent mood",
            "b) die castings",
            "c) die castings and permanent mold",
            "d) mud"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium alloys can be machined easily. They can also be fabricated into several structural shapes. They are attainable in the form of die castings, permanent mould and several other variants."
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "The atomic mass of magnesium is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1/43 u",
            "b) 47.867 u",
            "c) 24.3 u",
            "d) 51.9 u"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium is a very lightweight material compared to other materials like titanium and chromium. It does not have high strength. The atomic mass of magnesium is 24.3 u and titanium is 47.86 u."
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "___________ is not a magnesium ore.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bauxite",
            "b) Seawater",
            "c) Dolomite",
            "d) Magnesite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Magnesium is found in the earth’s crust in several places/countries across the world. There are several ores of magnesium available. Seawater, dolomite, magnesite are some examples. Bauxite is an aluminium ore."
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "Recycling of magnesium requires only _________ of energy required to make the primary substance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 24%",
            "b) 10%",
            "c) 88%",
            "d) 38%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Being able to recycle an element or material is a very advantageous prospect. Materials are recycled based on several factors including time, output, money etc. Magnesium requires only 10% of the energy required to make the primary equipment to be recycled."
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "Magnesium constitutes around __________ of ocean water in weight.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1.2%",
            "b) 23%",
            "c) 0.125%",
            "d) 7.4%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium is found in several parts of the world as ores. It is also present in water bodies. Magnesium constitutes around 0.125% of ocean water. The slat lake city of Utah, U.S.A contains 0.56% magnesium."
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is considered to be an ore of magnesium?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bornite",
            "b) Trihydrate",
            "c) Monohydrate",
            "d) Natural brines"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. The human body requires several nutrients and minerals in specified quantities depending upon several factors like age, gender etc. of the person. Deficiency of magnesium can lead to diabetes."
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "An important principle for cutting tools of magnesium alloys is ___________ the friction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) transferring",
            "b) scaling",
            "c) limiting",
            "d) increasing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Magnesium is never found in its natural state but instead is found in the form of ores. It has to be extracted from the ores. Natural brine is an ore of magnesium. Bornite is an ore of the element copper."
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": "For the first time in ___________ pure magnesium was obtained.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1599",
            "b) 2001",
            "c) 1932",
            "d) 1808"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Pure magnesium was first obtained in the year 1808. This was done by Sir Humphrey Davy, who was an English chemist. It was done by the process of electrolysis. Commercially, magnesium production began in 1914."
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "___________ is a process used to extract magnesium from its ore.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Nitride",
            "b) Farnsworth process",
            "c) Ferrosilicon process",
            "d) Mows process"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium is not found in a pure state. It has to be extracted from its ores. This can be done using several processes. Ferrosilicon process is a thermal reduction process used to extract magnesium."
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "Magnesium obtained in the electrolytic process has a minimum purity of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 69%",
            "b) 22.65%",
            "c) 99.98%",
            "d) 100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Electrolytic process is one of the several processes used to extract magnesium from seawater, brine or any other ores. If it is necessary this process can yield magnesium with a minimum purity of 99.98%."
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "Dolomite is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) magnesium carbonate",
            "b) magnesium and potassium chloride",
            "c) magnesium calcium carbonate",
            "d) magnesium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. A large number of products of magnesium alloys tend to be castings. They can be subjected to several types of treatments and their reaction to heat treatments results in positive properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "____________ is also called as Pidgeon.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Carbothermic process",
            "b) Electrolytic process",
            "c) Ferrosilicon process",
            "d) Achilles process"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium can be found commonly in various ores across the world. Dolomite is a magnesium calcium carbonate. Magnesium carbonate is magnesite. Carnallite is magnesium and potassium chloride."
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "Magnesium obtained through the ferrosilicon process can ensue in a minimum purity of ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 99.99%",
            "b) 78%",
            "c) 88.5%",
            "d) 100%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ferrosilicon extraction process of magnesium is also called Pidgeon. This process uses very less electricity. It involves reducing magnesium oxide through heat (in vacuum) using an alloy material that is made of both iron and silicon."
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "The resultant outputs of the carbothermic process are magnesium and __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) radium",
            "b) carbon dioxide",
            "c) vanadium",
            "d) carbon monoxide"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Magnesium is extracted through the ores found in places across the world. It is desirable to have a high amount of magnesium in its extraction. Magnesium obtained through the ferrosilicon process can have a minimum purity of 99.99%."
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "_____________ is also referred to as Hansgirg.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Electrolytic process",
            "b) Carbothermic process",
            "c) Ferrosilicon process",
            "d) Farnsworth process"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Carbothermic process is a thermal process used in the extraction of magnesium from its ores. In its process, magnesium oxide is obtained through a reduction from ores and is heated. It produces carbon monoxide apart from magnesium."
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "Magnesium alloys can be made into ___________ sophisticated structures compared to aluminium alloys.",
        "Options": [
            "a) zero",
            "b) less",
            "c) similar",
            "d) more"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Magnesium alloys can be made into much more sophisticated shapes compared to aluminium alloys. This is if proper equipment is used. This is due to the difference in properties like strength and structure."
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "Which of the following components of aircraft can be manufactured using magnesium?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Engine",
            "b) Wheels",
            "c) Engine, landing gear",
            "d) Landing gear"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium and magnesium alloys are used extensively in the aerospace industries due to their beneficial properties. They are used in the manufacturing of engine, landing gear and several other parts of an aircraft."
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "Magnesium __________ fuel efficiency.",
        "Options": [
            "a) maintains",
            "b) reduces",
            "c) improves",
            "d) does not affect"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: One of the advantages of using magnesium in industries is improved fuel efficiency. Fuel efficiency is a means of thermal efficiency. Fuel efficiency is the conversion of potential energy in fuel into work."
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "Magnesium can be found in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Greece, Antarctica",
            "b) USA",
            "c) USA, Greece",
            "d) Antarctica"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. Magnesium and magnesium alloys are utilized in several industries across the world. For example, it is used in the automobile industry, electrical industry and for photographic applications as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "The modulus of elasticity of pure magnesium is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 6,500,000 p.s.i",
            "b) 4,350,000 p.s.i",
            "c) 16500 ksi",
            "d) 330,00,000 p.s.i"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. It is not the most abundantly found element on earth. The most abundant metal on earth is aluminium and the most abundant element on planet earth is oxygen."
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "The density of pure magnesium is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4.506 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "b) 2.7 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "c) 12.35 lb./cu.in.",
            "d) 0.064 lb./cu.in."
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Magnesium is found in the form of ores in several places around the world. From the ores, magnesium is extracted. Magnesium can be found in Greece, the united states and several other countries."
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "Magnesium alloys have very __________ notch sensitivity in fatigue.",
        "Options": [
            "a) medium",
            "b) good",
            "c) poor",
            "d) conflicting"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The modulus of elasticity can be described as the resistance of a substance to elastic deformation when it is subjected to stress. The modulus of elasticity of magnesium is 6,500,000 p.s.i and that of aluminium is 4,350,000 p.s.i."
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Question": "Deficiency of magnesium can result in ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) versatile vision",
            "b) high blood pressure",
            "c) moderate blood Pressure",
            "d) high energy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The density of a material is the ratio of the amount of mass to the volume. The density of pure magnesium is 0.064 lb./cu.in. The density of titanium is 4.506 gram per cubic centimeter and that of aluminium is 2.7 gram per cubic centimeter."
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "Copper is a __________ element.",
        "Options": [
            "a) magnetic",
            "b) dull",
            "c) neuro-magnetic",
            "d) non-magnetic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Copper is an element in the periodic table that is non-magnetic in nature. It is also not dull and has a shiny texture. Copper is typically pinkish-orange in colour when newly exposed to the atmosphere."
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "The atomic number of copper is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11",
            "b) 13",
            "c) 29",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Copper is an element in the periodic table that has an atomic number of 29. 11 is the atomic number of sodium, 4 is the atomic number of beryllium and 14 is the atomic number of the element silicon."
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "The ultimate tensile strength of soft copper is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 63000 psi",
            "b) 45000 psi",
            "c) 29000 psi",
            "d) 50000 psi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The ultimate tensile strength of an element is also sometimes called the tensile strength of a material. The ultimate tensile strength of soft copper is 29000 pounds-force per square inch and that of aluminium is 45000 psi."
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "Copper is ____________ and ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) soft, malleable",
            "b) soft, hard",
            "c) brittle, malleable",
            "d) hard, malleable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Copper is an element that is soft and malleable in nature. It is an element that is not typically used extensively in manufacturing major structural components in an aircraft. It is highly used in electrical systems."
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "___________ and ___________ are ores of copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dolomite, bornite",
            "b) Bornite, chalcopyrite",
            "c) Chalcopyrite, dolomite",
            "d) Bornite, magnesite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Copper is very rarely found in its natural state. It has to be extracted from its ores through various processes. Copper has several ores in the world. Bornite and chalcopyrite are two ores of the element copper."
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "The melting point of copper is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1668°C",
            "b) 660°C",
            "c) 1085°C",
            "d) 2228°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The melting point of an element a point of temperature where the element melts. The melting point of copper is 1085°C. Aluminium has a melting point of 660°C and titanium’s melting point is 1668°C. "
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "Copper is frequently alloyed with __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) zinc",
            "b) aluminium",
            "c) helium",
            "d) vanadium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Copper is an element that can be alloyed with several other elements. It has many advantages. Copper is very frequently alloyed with the element zinc. Brass and bronze are some examples of alloyed materials."
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "The density of copper is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4.506 gram per cubic centimetre",
            "b) 2.7 gram per cubic centimetre",
            "c) 9.9 gram per cubic centimetre",
            "d) 8.9 gram per cubic centimetre"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Density is the ratio of mass to volume of a substance. The density of copper is 8.9 gram per cubic centimetre. The density of aluminium is 2.7 gram per cubic centimetre and titanium is 4.506 gram per cubic centimetre."
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "Copper is a ____________ of electricity.",
        "Options": [
            "a) bad conductor",
            "b) good conductor",
            "c) typical insulator",
            "d) medium conductor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. Copper is an element that is typically ductile in nature. It is due to the nature in which the atoms of copper are arranged. Ductility of a material is the ability to be shaped or drawn into wires."
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "Copper is corrosion ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) prone",
            "b) generator",
            "c) susceptible",
            "d) resistant"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. Copper has several ores across the world. One of the ores of copper is cuprite. Cuprite happens to be a minor ore of the element copper. Copper is a conductor of both heat and electricity."
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "The boiling point of copper is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3287°C",
            "b) 2470°C",
            "c) 2562°C",
            "d) 1687°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: One of the most beneficial properties of copper is its conductive nature. Copper is a very good conductor of electricity. It also has very good thermal conductivity. This makes it desirable to use in several industries."
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "Sulfide ores contain around _____ copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9 – 10%",
            "b) 8 – 12%",
            "c) 4 – 5%",
            "d) 0.5 – 2%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Copper is usually never found in a natural state. Copper is found in several ores across the world including sulfide ore which contains 0.5 – 2% of copper. It has to undergo several processes to attain purity."
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "The first process in extraction of an element from ore is typically ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) roasting",
            "b) electrolysis",
            "c) crushing",
            "d) smelting"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Crushing is one of the first things done in the extraction process of copper from its ore. Copper ore is crushed to a particular required size. Crushing is done to separate the particles to make it easier to obtain the pure material."
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "Which of the following techniques are used in the extraction of copper?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Refining, down process",
            "b) Smelting, vacuum pump",
            "c) Roasting, refining",
            "d) Roasting"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The extraction of copper from its ores is done through several techniques that include roasting, refining, smelting, crushing etc. Dow’s process is done to obtain the substance magnesium, not copper."
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "___________ is a sulfide ore of copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Chalcocite",
            "b) Cuprite",
            "c) Magnesite",
            "d) Azurite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Copper is found in several ores. Some of the ores are chalcocite, cuprite, bornite, chalcopyrite etc. Magnesite and dolomite are not ores of copper, they are ores of the element magnesium."
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "Sulfide ores are typically processed through a technique known as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) cathode",
            "b) pyrometallurgy",
            "c) hydrometallurgy",
            "d) zarconsis"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sulfide ores are usually processed through the technique known as pyrometallurgy. Pyrometallurgy involves several processes like froth flotation, thickening, smelting, electrolysis etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "Copper ores typically contain less than _________ of copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.15%",
            "b) 0.2%",
            "c) 1%",
            "d) 0.4%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Copper is found in ores in the earth’s crust. Copper oxides are found in considerable amounts but do not have a high concentration. Typically, all copper ores contain less than 1% of copper."
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "Smelting is done to eradicate unwanted materials like ___________ to the fullest extent possible.",
        "Options": [
            "a) copper",
            "b) copper and gangue minerals",
            "c) sulfur",
            "d) sulfur and gangue minerals"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. Oxide ores are typically processed using hydrometallurgy. Hydrometallurgy involves using water-based solutions to purify copper. This technique contains processes like solvent extraction etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "The final output after processing of copper ores to be purified produces around ____________ pure copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100%",
            "b) 45%",
            "c) 99.9%",
            "d) 86%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Smelting is done to eradicate unwanted materials like sulfur and gangue minerals to the fullest extent possible. The output of the smelting phase is called copper matte. It is a combination of sulfur, copper and iron."
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": "Muntz metal consists of ___________ copper and __________ zinc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 75%, 25%",
            "b) 25%, 75%",
            "c) 50%, 50%",
            "d) 60%, 40%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Muntz metal is a type of brass. It consists of both copper and zinc. Composition wise, there is 60% copper and 40% zinc. It has several distinct properties which vary depending on if it is heat-treated or not."
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "Manganese bronze is remarkably ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) difficult to forge",
            "b) weak",
            "c) strong",
            "d) low in zinc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Manganese bronze is a type of brass that typically has a high amount of zinc. It has various good properties, one of the most important properties being its remarkably high strength. It is not a weak alloy."
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "Brass that consists of around ___________ zinc is highly ductile in nature.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 49-50%",
            "b) 15-18%",
            "c) 30-35%",
            "d) 1-2%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Brass is an alloy of copper. The properties of the alloy like ductility vary depending on the composition of the alloy. Brass consisting of around 30% to 35% zinc tends to be highly ductile in nature."
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "The ultimate tensile strength for heat-treated muntz metal is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 80,000 p.s.i",
            "b) 20,000 p.s.i",
            "c) 60,000 p.s.i",
            "d) 57,000 p.s.i"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Muntz is a metal consisting of both copper and zinc. It has several advantageous properties, like being corrosion-resistant under certain conditions and possessing high strength when subjected to heat treatments."
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "Manganese bronze is made of around 57% to 60% of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) lead",
            "b) manganese",
            "c) copper",
            "d) zinc"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Brass is an alloy. It is a copper alloy. Brass is typically made almost entirety two elements. The two primary elements are copper and zinc. Not aluminium."
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "The density of beryllium copper is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 8.24 gram per cubic centimeters",
            "b) 26 gram per cubic centimeters",
            "c) 13.24 gram per cubic centimeters",
            "d) 4.98 gram per cubic centimeters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Manganese bronze is made of several elements in varying quantities of combinations. It is made of around 57% to 60% copper, 0.8% to 2.0% iron and also approximately 0.5% manganese (maximum)."
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "Which of the following are properties of beryllium copper?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Low-strength, non-magnetic",
            "b) Low-strength, magnetic",
            "c) Magnetic, high-strength",
            "d) High-strength, non-magnetic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Beryllium copper is an alloy of copper. It has a density of 8.24 gram per cubic centimeters. It is made by adding various metals and elements to obtain certain kinds of specific properties that make it better."
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "A casting type of manganese bronze called manganese-aluminium alloy includes approximately __________ of tin.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 50%",
            "b) 0.2%",
            "c) 0.5%",
            "d) 5%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Beryllium copper is an alloy. It has numerous advantageous or desirable properties. One of the advantageous properties of beryllium copper is its high strength. Another property is its non-magnetic nature."
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "Beryllium copper consists of around ___________ of beryllium.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.5%",
            "b) 2 to 2.25%",
            "c) 10 to 15%",
            "d) 26 to30%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Manganese bronze is an alloy of copper. It is also available in different variants, one of which is manganese-aluminium alloy. It is made of approximately 0.5% of tin and approximately 0.2% of lead (maximum)."
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "The ultimate tensile strength of sand cast Hy-Ten-Sl-Bronze is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 75,000 p.s.i",
            "b) 115,000 p.s.i",
            "c) 999,000 p.s.i",
            "d) 229,000 p.s.i"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Beryllium copper is an alloy that consists of around 2% to 2.25% of beryllium. It is a non-magnetic and high-strength alloy. It is also attainable in several other forms like sheets, strips, bars etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "Which of the following are properties of Hy-Ten-Sl-Bronze?",
        "Options": [
            "a) wear-prone, corrosive",
            "b) wear-resistant, non-corrosive",
            "c) wear-resistant, corrosive",
            "d) wear-prone, non-corrosive"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hy-Ten-Sl-Bronze is an alloy that has an extremely high amount of strength. The ultimate tensile strength of sand cast Hy-Ten-Sl-Bronze is 115,000 p.s.i. This alloy is also available in four other types/variants."
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "A type of casting of manganese bronze called manganese-aluminium alloy consists of approximately __________ of aluminium",
        "Options": [
            "a) 60 to 68%",
            "b) 2 to 4%",
            "c) 3 to 7.5%",
            "d) 15%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The above statement is correct. One of the beneficial properties of manganese bronze is it’s resistance to corrosion. It is also known for being an alloy that has remarkable strength and toughness."
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "Which of the following elements is occasionally present in brass is minor amounts?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cooper, lead",
            "b) Iron, vanadium",
            "c) Lead",
            "d) Iron, lead"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Hy-Ten-Sl-Bronze is an alloy that is non-corrosive in nature. It is also known to be wear-resistant. Hy-Ten-Sl-Bronze is also an alloy that is easily machinable in nature and has high hardness."
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Question": "____________ is also known as Tobin bronze.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Red clay",
            "b) Sand",
            "c) Uranium",
            "d) Naval brass"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Naval brass is also known as Tobin bronze. It has several qualities that are beneficial in the manufacturing and construction of aerospace components. Naval brass has wonderful machining qualities."
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "Red brass contains around ____________ % antimony.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.75",
            "b) 0.20",
            "c) 0.25",
            "d) 0.15"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Red brass is an alloy that is also sometimes referred to as a bronze material due to its quantity of tin. Red brass contains around 0.25 per-cent of antimony and around 84 to 86 percent of copper."
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "Red brass (casting) has a UTS of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15,00 pound-force per square inch",
            "b) 29 pound-force per square inch",
            "c) 30,000 pound-force per square inch",
            "d) 10000 pound-force per square inch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: UTS refers to Ultimate tensile strength. Red brass (casting) has an ultimate tensile strength of 30,000 pound-force per square inch. Red brass is also an alloy that typically has good casting properties."
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "___________ is used in manufacturing components like fuel line fittings.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Copper",
            "b) Red brass",
            "c) Red plate",
            "d) Bronze"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Naval bronze is an alloy material. It is used in manufacturing several components due to its good properties, but it is not stronger than manganese bronze."
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "Copper alloys containing a large amount of __________ are called bronze.",
        "Options": [
            "a) lead",
            "b) phosphorus",
            "c) tin",
            "d) iron"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Red brass is an alloy that is used in manufacturing components like fuel line fittings. It is a material that machines well. Apart from being used in fuel line fittings, it is also used in manufacturing oil line fittings."
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "Naval brass is used in manufacturing ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) bolts and studs",
            "b) tires",
            "c) bolts",
            "d) bolts and tires"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Bronze is a copper alloy that contains a large amount of tin. Bronze also contains smaller amounts of materials like lead, zinc, phosphorus, etc. They are different variations present depending on the composition."
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": "Gun-metal contains around ___________ % of zinc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.9",
            "b) 4-14",
            "c) 6-9",
            "d) 1-3"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Naval brass is an alloy material. It is used in the manufacturing/making of several components like bolts, studs, nuts, etc. It also can be used in making components that come in contact with NaCl."
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "Naval brass contains around ____________ of lead.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.5%",
            "b) 0.10%",
            "c) 0.20%",
            "d) 10%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Gun-metal is an alloy that is made/consists of several components in varying quantities. Gun-metal contains around 1 to 3 per-cent of zinc. It also contains approximately 9 to 11 per-cent of tin."
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "Gun-metal (casting) has a yield point of ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 30,000 pound-force per square inch",
            "b) 15,000 pound-force per square inch",
            "c) 6000 pound-force per square inch",
            "d) 1000 pound-force per square inch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Naval brass consists of around 0.2 per-cent lead. It also contains approximately 0.10 per-cent iron. Naval brass also has some impurities present that account for about not more than 0.1 per-cent."
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "Naval brass has __________ strength compared to commercial brass.",
        "Options": [
            "a) lower",
            "b) better",
            "c) similar",
            "d) lenient"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Gun-metal casting has a yield point of 15,000 pound-force per square inch. Gun-metal (castings) also have a UTI (Ultimate tensile strength) of around 30,000 pound-force per square inch."
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "Gun-metal should not be utilized in temperatures above __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 260°C",
            "b) 550°C",
            "c) 260°F",
            "d) 150°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Naval brass is an alloy that in some considerations, is better than commercial brass. Naval brass has better strength when compared to commercial brass. It also has greater corrosion resistance than commercial brass."
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "Red brass contains ______________ of zinc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 40-50%",
            "b) 4-6%",
            "c) 1-2%",
            "d) 30-35%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are different types of bronzes based on their composition. Aluminium bronze is a kind of bronze where aluminium is one of the dominant elements."
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "Gun-metal contains around _______________ copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 9-11%",
            "b) 0.2%",
            "c) 86-89%",
            "d) 5-10%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Gun-metal is an alloy metal that cannot be used at all temperatures. More specifically, gun-metal should not be utilized in temperatures above 260°C. For certain components, it cannot be annealed as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "Phosphor bronze can be utilized in the manufacturing of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) skids",
            "b) tires",
            "c) rubber wheels",
            "d) bolts"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Phosphor bronze is used in the manufacturing of several components. Some of the components are units like bolts, electrical contacts, etc. It is used in several industries across the world."
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "Phosphor bronze casting alloy is also known as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) aluminium",
            "b) barrel",
            "c) leaded gunmetal",
            "d) tripper metal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The bronze material phosphor bronze casting alloy is also known as leaded gunmetal. It has several advantages due to its composition, such as it tends to machine better in terms of ease than gunmetal."
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "Phosphor bronze contains approximately _________ % of phosphorous.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 3.5",
            "b) 0.9",
            "c) 0.05-0.5",
            "d) 26"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Phosphor bronze consists of several different elements. It contains approximately 0.05-0.5% of phosphorus and a minimum of 3.5% of tin. Phosphor bronze also contains other elements like iron as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "The UTS of phosphor bronze casting alloy is _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20,000 pounds per square inch",
            "b) 40,000 pounds per square inch",
            "c) 1,000 pounds per square inch",
            "d) 599 pounds per square inch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Phosphor bronze casting alloy, which is also known as leaded phosphor bronze is an advantageous material due to its strength, low coefficient of friction, etc. It can be used in making such materials because it is resistant to salt-water corrosion."
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "Aluminium bronze contains approximately 6.5-11% of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) titanium",
            "b) manganese",
            "c) aluminium",
            "d) vanadium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ultimate tensile strength of phosphor bronze casting alloy is 40,000 pounds per square inch. Phosphor bronze casting alloy is used in the manufacturing of components that require good strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "Phosphor bronze contains approximately __________ % of copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.2",
            "b) 0.1",
            "c) 36",
            "d) 94"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Aluminium bronze is a bronze material that contains various elements like aluminium, manganese, etc. Aluminium bronze contains approximately 6.5-11% of aluminium. It also contains a maximum of 2% manganese."
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "Phosphor bronze casting alloy contains approximately __________ % of zinc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0-0.3",
            "b) 0.75",
            "c) 1.5-4.5",
            "d) 45"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium bronze is a bronze that possesses greater resistance to corrosion than manganese bronze. Hence, in industries and manufacturing, it is used accordingly."
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "Aluminium bronze is accessible in the frame of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) taps",
            "b) bars and plates",
            "c) bars",
            "d) taps and bars"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Copper is a major component in phosphor bronze. It contains approximately 94% of copper. Phosphor bronze also contains a maximum of 0.20% lead and also 0.10% iron composite-wise."
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "A anneal of ____________ temperature is enough to deter the phenomenon of season cracking.",
        "Options": [
            "a) high",
            "b) low",
            "c) medium",
            "d) unusual"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Phosphor bronze casting alloy is made of several elements like copper, tin, zinc, lead, phosphor, iron, nickel, etc. Phosphor bronze casting alloy usually contains approximately 1.5-4.5% of zinc."
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Question": "Aluminium bronze casting alloys have a UTS of __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 85,000 pounds per square inch",
            "b) 10,000 pounds per square inch",
            "c) 23,000 pounds per square inch",
            "d) 1,000 pounds per square inch"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Aluminium bronze is a bronze variant that is accessible in several forms. It is accessible especially in the form of bars and plates. It can typically also be found in the form of rods, sheets etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "Aluminium bronze consists of around ___________ of iron.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4%",
            "b) 7%",
            "c) 0.6%",
            "d) 60%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The phenomenon of season cracking is highly unwanted and detrimental to the usual requirement or process desired. Hence, one way to deal with season cracking is low temperature anneal."
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "___________ of copper is present in Aluminium bronze casting alloy.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10.5-12%",
            "b) 78%",
            "c) 2-5%",
            "d) 26%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium bronze casting alloys are materials that are known to possess the quality of good strength. They are known to have a UTS- ultimate tensile strength of 85,000 pounds per square inch."
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "Materials like brasses and bronzes experiencing cracking after being used for a long duration is called __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) factual cracking",
            "b) residual cracking",
            "c) season cracking",
            "d) crack cracking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Aluminium bronze consists of around 4% of iron. It is also known to have a maximum of 4% iron. The maximum value of tin present in aluminium bronze is 0.60% of the total material in the composition."
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "Inconel is an alloy that contains nickel and ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) iron",
            "b) steel",
            "c) zinc",
            "d) chromium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Inconel is a nickel alloy that contains the elements nickel and chromium. It is an alloy that has several other advantageous properties like having favourable strength at normal as well as elevated temperatures."
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Question": "The atomic number of nickel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5",
            "b) 40",
            "c) 28",
            "d) 13"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The atomic number of the element nickel is 28. 23 is the atomic number of the element vanadium, whereas 40 is the atomic number of zirconium and 13 is the atomic number of the element aluminium."
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is not a nickel ore?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pentlandite",
            "b) Chalcopyrite",
            "c) Rutile",
            "d) Pyrrhotite"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The element nickel has several ores. Pentlandite, chalcopyrite, and Pyrrhotite are some of the ores. Rutile is not an ore of nickel, it is an ore of the element titanium. Naturally, pure nickel is found in very small amounts."
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "Monel is an alloy that consists of nickel and __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) brass",
            "b) copper",
            "c) bronze",
            "d) titanium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  One of the most desirable and widely appreciated qualities of most nickel alloys is their resistance to corrosion. They tend to have very good resistance to corrosion."
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "The young’s modulus of nickel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 69 GPa",
            "b) 120 GPa",
            "c) 200 GPa",
            "d) 159 GPa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Monel is an alloy of nickel. It consists of nickel and copper (High amounts). It is known for having favourable resistance to corrosion and also very great working properties. Another alloy of nickel is Dura nickel."
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "Nickel is a __________ material.",
        "Options": [
            "a) soft",
            "b) non-ductile",
            "c) non-metallic",
            "d) ductile"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The young’s modulus of the element nickel is 200 GPa. 69 GPa is typically Young’s modulus of aluminium alloys. 120 GPa tends to be the young’s modulus of several different titanium alloys."
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "___________ is often used in the manufacturing of aircraft engine exhaust collectors.",
        "Options": [
            "a) K Monel",
            "b) Monel",
            "c) Inconel",
            "d) T Monel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: K Monel is a nickel alloy. It is also an alloy that is non-magnetic in nature. This can be a useful property as this alloy can be used in manufacturing materials close to a compass."
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "K Monel is an alloy that includes nickel __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) copper",
            "b) aluminium",
            "c) iron",
            "d) copper-aluminium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Nickel is an element that is ductile in nature. It is also not a soft element. It is a hard material. Nickel is also a metallic element that is lustrous in appearance. It is a transition element."
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "The melting point of nickel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 660°C",
            "b) 1445°C",
            "c) 1668°C",
            "d) 1300°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The nickel alloy Inconel is used in the manufacturing of aircraft engine components, specifically the aircraft engine exhaust collectors. It is often used due to its advantageous properties like good strength."
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Question": "The approximate percentage of chromium present in Inconel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 42%",
            "b) 6.5%",
            "c) 0.25%",
            "d) 13%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The approximate amount of chromium present in this nickel-based alloy Inconel is 13%. 0.25% is the approximate amount of manganese present in it. 6.5% is the proportion of iron present in Inconel."
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "Machining of the nickel alloy Monel can be done __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) with hardships",
            "b) trapped",
            "c) without hardship",
            "d) impossibly"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Monel is a nickel-based alloy that has several advantageous properties. One of the properties of the nickel-based alloy is its reaction to machining. Monel can typically be machined easily."
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "The melting point of K Monel is around ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2400-2460°C",
            "b) 1245°F",
            "c) 2400-2460°F",
            "d) 1064-1890°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The melting point of any material is the point of temperature at which the substance changes phase or state. The melting point of K Monel is typically in between the range of 2400-2460°F."
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "The density of Inconel is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 22 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "b) 8.51 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "c) 123 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "d) 45 gram per cubic centimeter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Monel is not a material that is used frequently in the aviation industry or more specifically the manufacturing of aircrafts. It is used for other general purposes."
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "The approximate amount of aluminium present in K Monel is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 26%",
            "b) 0.15%",
            "c) 2.75%",
            "d) 99%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The density, weight, etc. of a material are the physical properties of the material. The density of Inconel is  8.51 gram per cubic centimeter. The weight of Inconel per cubic inch is 0.13 kilograms."
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "Monel is utilized in ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) non-chemical applications",
            "b) schools",
            "c) aerospace purposes",
            "d) industries"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The approximate amount of aluminium present in K Monel is 2.75%. The typical amount of carbon present in K Monel is 0.15%. The approximate amount of manganese present in K Monel is 0.85%."
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "Inconel is a heat _____________ material.",
        "Options": [
            "a) conducting",
            "b) accepting",
            "c) resisting",
            "d) exhausting"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Inconel is a nickel-based alloy and is a non-ferrous material. This is because the amount of iron content present in Inconel is generally considered to be negligible."
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "It is possible to harden K Monel through ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) clod treatment",
            "b) gold treatment",
            "c) proof treatment",
            "d) heat treatment"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Monel is a nickel-based alloy that is used for several applications. It is a material that has several advantages like being remarkably resistant to corrosion. It is used in industries across the world."
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Question": "The density of rolled Monel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 19.1 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "b) 8.9 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "c) 32 gram per cubic centimeter",
            "d) 8.8 gram per cubic centimeter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Inconel is an alloy/material that is known to be typically heat-resisting. It is also defined by several other qualities like being a very good corrosion-resistant material or having a good strength level."
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "K Monel is typically manufactured by adding a little __________ in Monel.",
        "Options": [
            "a) aluminium",
            "b) titanium",
            "c) copper",
            "d) silicon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: K Monel is a metal that can be hardened through heat treatment. This is a process that involves several various steps at different temperatures and time periods that tend to be very specific."
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "K Monel is a ___________ material.",
        "Options": [
            "a) ferrous",
            "b) non-ferrous",
            "c) proxy-ferrous",
            "d) anti-ferrous"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The density of the nickel-copper based alloy varies depending on whether it is cast or rolled. The density of rolled Monel is 8.9 gram per cubic centimeter. The density of cast Monel is 8.8 gram per cubic centimeter."
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "Monel consists of approximately _________ of copper.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 30%",
            "b) 1.4%",
            "c) 0.1%",
            "d) 16%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: K Monel is an alloy that consists principally of nickel, copper and aluminium. The alloy K Monel is manufactured by adding a little quantity of aluminium in the nickel copper-based alloy Monel."
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "Welding on Inconel is done __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) with difficulty",
            "b) easily",
            "c) hardly",
            "d) wretchedly"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: K Monel is a non-ferrous material that is nickel, copper and aluminium alloy. It is known to have several good properties like being a good resistor of corrosion and also has a property of being non-magnetic."
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "The amount of nickel present in Inconel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.2%",
            "b) 0.25%",
            "c) 46%",
            "d) 79.5%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The amount of nickel present in the nickel-based alloy Inconel is 79.5% of the composition. The amount of manganese present is 0.25%. Silicon is also present approximately in the same quantity. Copper makes around 0.2%"
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "At normal temperatures, the material K Monel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) magnetic",
            "b) active",
            "c) non-magnetic",
            "d) corrosion prone"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The non-ferrous alloy K Monel is non-magnetic in nature at normal temperatures. The magnetic permeability of K Monel is 1. It is the same as that of air. This is helpful when the metal has to be located near a compass."
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "The melting point of Monel is around __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1220°F",
            "b) 2355-2566°C",
            "c) 2370-2460°F",
            "d) 4500°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The nickel-based alloy Monel also has a high copper content. It has properties that make it good to use in industries like good strength. The melting point of Monel is approximately around 2370-2460°F."
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "The melting point of Inconel is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1090°F",
            "b) 2540°F",
            "c) 2900°F",
            "d) 2540°C"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Monel is an alloy that resembles mild steel in several ways when it comes to working properties. For example, it is similar in cold working properties like forming and bending."
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "The approximate amount of nickel present in Monel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1%",
            "b) 0.15%",
            "c) 67%",
            "d) 33%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The melting point of the nickel-based alloy Inconel is approximately 2540°F. It is a heat-resisting metal. The melting point, density, weight, modulus of elasticity, etc. are the physical properties of the metal."
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "The approximate amount of copper present in K Monel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.85%",
            "b) 0.9%",
            "c) 46%",
            "d) 29%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The approximate amount of nickel present in Monel is 67% in the composition. The percentage of manganese present is 1%. The percentage of carbon present in Monel is around 0.15%."
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "Inconel ____________ high strength and high temperatures.",
        "Options": [
            "a) generates",
            "b) radiates",
            "c) preserves",
            "d) hooks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is not possible to harden the alloy Inconel by heat treatment. Inconel has to be subjected to cold working to be hardened. It is a process involving heating and cooling at different temperatures."
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "The density of K Monel is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 90.34 grams per cubic centimetre",
            "b) 44 grams per cubic centimetre",
            "c) 18.2 grams per cubic centimetre",
            "d) 8.47 grams per cubic centimetre"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The approximate amount of copper present in K Monel is 29%. The amount of manganese present in K Monel tends to be around 0.85%. The approximate amount of nickel present in it is around 66%."
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "Monel can be welded ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) rarely",
            "b) easily",
            "c) with difficulty",
            "d) timelessly"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Inconel has a habit of retaining high amounts of strength at higher temperatures. This characteristic of the nickel-chromium alloy is useful in several applications like the manufacturing of engines etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "___________ alleviates internal stress.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Annealing",
            "b) Conducting",
            "c) Bombarding",
            "d) Inundating"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The density of the alloy K Monel is 8.47 grams per cubic centimetre. The weight of the material per cubic inches is 0.14 kilograms. The melting point of K Monel tends to be between 2400-2460°F."
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "___________ is not a method of welding of Monel.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Oxyacetylene",
            "b) Cold-stiffening",
            "c) Carbon-arc welding",
            "d) Metallic-arc welding"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The alloy Monel can be welded easily. There are several methods used in welding Monel. The type of welding method chosen depends on several factors including the type of material that has to be made."
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "Heating of alloys that have high nickel content should be done in __________ atmospheres.",
        "Options": [
            "a) sulphur free",
            "b) low temperatures",
            "c) sulphur rich",
            "d) sulphur infused"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The process of annealing alleviates internal stress. Annealing can be done to several alloys of nickel like Inconel, Monel and K Monel. Annealing of metals is done by heating and quenching at specific temperatures depending on the material."
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "Inconel is softened by heating up to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1800°C",
            "b) 1800°F",
            "c) 180°C",
            "d) 180°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: There are different types of welding the material Monel. The three methods are Oxyacetylene, carbon-arc welding and metallic-arc welding. The method used depends on the material that has to be made."
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "Inconel is accessible commercially in which of the following shapes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tube",
            "b) Wires",
            "c) Z-shapes",
            "d) Tubes and wires"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Inconel is accessible in the markets in several forms and shapes. It is also available in tubes and wires. Inconel in tube form it is available in welded and cold drawn seamless form and wire in cold drawn."
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "Monel is used in making ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) oil coolers",
            "b) rivets",
            "c) oil coolers and rivets",
            "d) rubber tires"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Monel is a nickel-copper alloy. It is used in making both oil coolers and rivets. Monel is used in making several other components apart from oil coolers and rivets like stainers etc. to be used in industries."
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "___________ metal is used near compasses.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Monel",
            "b) Inconel",
            "c) K Monel",
            "d) Iron"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: K Monel is used in components and structures that are near a compass. This is because K Monel is non-magnetic in nature. K Monel is a nickel-copper-aluminium based alloy. It is made by adding a little bit of aluminium to Monel."
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "Inconel weighs ___________ corrosion-resistant steel.",
        "Options": [
            "a) less than",
            "b) more than",
            "c) equal to",
            "d) double of"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Nickel is suitable for manufacturing several instruments and components including mobile phones and power generators. This is due to its good strength at high temperatures."
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "___________ is a relatively non-complicated way of joining (Monel) where strength is not necessary.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Welding",
            "b) Carbon-arc",
            "c) Soft soldering",
            "d) Oxyacetylene"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Inconel weighs slightly more than corrosion-resistant steel. This is a disadvantage of the material. Inconel is a chromium-nickel alloy. It is non-ferrous due to its low iron content and also has low carbon content."
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "____________ alloy/alloys are corrosion resistant in atmosphere and saltwater.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inconel",
            "b) Monel",
            "c) Steel",
            "d) Inconel and K Monel"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Soft soldering is used frequently. It is a relatively non-complicated way of joining monel where strength is not necessary and several characteristic properties like contamination are not affecting it."
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "Soft soldering of Monel should not be done when the material is subjected to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) low stress",
            "b) ideal properties",
            "c) vibration",
            "d) vibration and ideal properties"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Nickel alloys can be used extensively in the transportation industry. It is used in making heavy trucks, railway tracks and ship manufacturing. Nickel alloys are also used in jet engines."
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "Inconel springs can be used at temperatures between ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 600-700°C",
            "b) 100-200°F",
            "c) 50-150°F",
            "d) 600-700°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The nickel-based alloys Inconel and K Monel are both corrosion resistant in nature. They are corrosion resistant in normal atmospheric conditions as well as saltwater. This is an advantageous property."
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "____________ can be used as a lubricant when Monel is subjected to boring, drilling, etc.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Carbon oil",
            "b) Sulphurized oil",
            "c) Vegetable oil",
            "d) Deep oil"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Soft soldering of Monel should not be done when the material is subjected to vibration. The same applies rule applies when the material is subjected to high stresses. Soft soldering is not very strong."
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "K Monel sheet can be welded satisfactorily by ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) oxyacetylene",
            "b) cold-rolling",
            "c) anomaxicity",
            "d) cold-rolling and Anomaxicity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Inconel springs can be used at temperatures between 600-700°F. Inconel is also suitable for usage due to its various advantageous properties like being corrosion resistant and its non-magnetic nature."
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "____________ is formed on the surface of Inconel if heated above 700°F in an oxidizing atmosphere.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Carbon",
            "b) Chromium oxide",
            "c) Hydrogen peroxide",
            "d) Nitric oxide"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sulphurized oil can be used as a lubricant and should be used extensively when Monel is being subjected to machine work activities like boring, drilling, etc. For some activities, other oils are enough."
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "K Monel is accessible as ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Forgings",
            "b) Z-shape",
            "c) U-shape",
            "d) T-shape"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: K Monel sheet can be welded satisfactorily by Oxyacetylene. There are different methods of making the flux required for this. The weld that is obtained as a by-product in this reacts to heat treatment."
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "Inconel welds are cleaned after fabrication by submerging in a _________ cold nitric acid solution.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20%",
            "b) 50%",
            "c) 99%",
            "d) 12%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Chromium oxide is formed on the surface of the nickel-chromium based alloy when it is heated above 700°F in an oxidizing atmosphere. There are different methods like pickling to remove it."
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "The atomic number of zinc is ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 25",
            "b) 13",
            "c) 104",
            "d) 30"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The atomic number of zinc is 30. 25 is the atomic number of the element manganese. 13 is the atomic number of aluminium. Rutherfordium is the synthetic chemical element with an atomic number of 104."
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "The density of Zinc is ____________ at room temperature.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.7 gram per cubic centimetre",
            "b) 6.52 gram per cubic centimetre",
            "c) 7.14 gram per cubic centimetre",
            "d) 0.44 gram per cubic centimetre"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The density of the element zinc is 7.14 gram per cubic centimetre. 2.7 gram per cubic centimetre is the density of aluminium. 6.52 gram per cubic centimetre is the density of the element zirconium."
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "Zinc in the form of ores can be found in which of the following places?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Antarctica",
            "b) Canada",
            "c) Canada and Russia",
            "d) Russia and Antarctica"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Zinc is found in the form of ores in various places across the world. It is frequently found in countries like Canada, Russia, the United States of America, etc. The ore has to undergo several processes to obtain pure zinc."
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "Zinc is alloyed with which of the following elements frequently?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vanadium",
            "b) Copper",
            "c) Helium",
            "d) Rutherfordium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The above statement is incorrect. Zinc is an element that is lustrous. It is solid at room temperature and is also slightly brittle in nature. Zinc is a post-transition element in the periodic table."
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "Which of the following are ores of zinc?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cobaltite",
            "b) Erythrite",
            "c) Marmatite",
            "d) Litharge"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Zinc is often alloyed with the element copper to obtain the metal alloy brass. It is used extensively for several purposes like decorative items. Zinc is also alloyed with several elements like tin, aluminium etc."
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "The melting point of zinc is __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1495°C",
            "b) 1445°C",
            "c) 787.1°C",
            "d) 787.1°F"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Zinc and most elements are rarely found in their pure state, they are found in the form of ores. Zinc is also found in the form of like in like Marmatite, zinc sulphide (ZnS), Calamine, etc. in different places."
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "Zinc is ___________ in colour.",
        "Options": [
            "a) black",
            "b) yellow",
            "c) bluish-silver",
            "d) red"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Zinc has been used extensively in the past and is being used in the present as well. Zinc was not produced on a bigger scale until the twelfth century but was used before that as well."
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "Pure zinc in metallic form was discovered by a __________ chemist.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Persian",
            "b) Indian",
            "c) American",
            "d) German"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The melting point of an element is the point of temperature at which the phase of the element changes. The melting point of zinc is 787.1°F. 1495°C is the melting point of the element cobalt."
    }
]